<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Rill Online</title>
  <description><![CDATA[Rill&#39;s Ramblings]]></description>
  <link>http://rillonline.github.io</link>
  <generator>http://www.olai.in</generator>
  <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 02:41:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <atom:link href="http://rillonline.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Day 3]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/day-3/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/day-3/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 03:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>God&rsquo;s Rant.</h3>

<h4>Reading</h4>

<p>Isaiah 58:1-12</p>

<p>I am imagining Mom standing in the family room, looking around at the kids and the mess. There are papers everywhere. Empty cans and bottles, pizza boxes, wrappers, half-eaten bags of potato chips. The homework is scattered about. Everyone is peering into their own screen.</p>

<p>Mom says, &ldquo;Clean this place up!&rdquo; and leaves. She runs some errands, Comes back in and says, &ldquo;The groceries are in the car. They need to be unloaded.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Nobody moves. Nothing happens. The kids continue to peer into their screens. In fact, the room looks worse than it did when Mom left.</p>

<p>Mom loses it and says, &ldquo;Is this what I told you to do? Didn&rsquo;t I tell you to clean up?&rdquo;</p>

<p>It seems to me that this is the very thing God is doing in this reading. The people  have out their sackcloth and their ashes. They&rsquo;re expecting all kinds of results from their fastin. Nothing&rsquo;s happening because God has not described fasting as an activity of ashes and sackcloth. God has seen the kind of fast that people need to be about is taking care of other people. They are taking care of themselves and basically doing everybody else in.</p>

<p>God says, &ldquo;Enough, I&rsquo;ve had enough. You people just don&rsquo;t seem to get it. Now let Me remind you again what a true fast is all about.&rdquo;</p>

<p>It all boils down to taking care of the people less fortunate than yourself. And this may include your relative. God goes on to say that if you indeed do all these things, amazing things will happen. God likens it to a desert becoming a garden&mdash;a very appropriate metaphor for the Middle East.</p>

<p>One of the things we will be looking at in our Lenten journey is an opportunity to discern what sort of a fast God has in mind for each of us—not one that means abstaining from food and putting on sackcloth and ashes, but of living the life and the spirit.</p>

<h4>Let us pray. ..</h4>

<p>O God, may I learn this Lent how you would have me walk by the spirit. Amen.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/day-3/">Day 3</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Day 1 (Ash Wednesday)]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/day-1-ash-wednesday/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/day-1-ash-wednesday/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 19:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>Create in Me</h3>

<h4>Reading</h4>

<p>Psalm 51</p>

<h4>Create, Renew, Restore, Uphold</h4>

<p>This is what we desire for ourselves:</p>

<ul>
<li>to renew our souls,<br></li>
<li>to have God recreate our hearts so they are clean and fresh,<br></li>
<li>to be restored to a genuine relationship with God,<br></li>
<li>to be upheld in the joy of being present before God,<br></li>
<li>to know deep in our hearts that God is for us and we can trust that God is for us.<br></li>
</ul>

<p>This assurance comes in the midst of Ash Wednesday. In the midst of knowing all about my own weaknesses, my own faults, my own failures, my own inability to do what I think I ought to do—to do the things I want to do—too do the things I think are right and good and wholesome to do.</p>

<p>Ash Wednesday is a day of facing my failures, my inadequacies, my hypocrisies—everything about me which is dirty and awful and miserable—all those things I hide from the world. But God knows. God knows all these things well. Nevertheless I can go to God and say,</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Have mercy on me. Create in me a clean heart. Renew, restore, uphold. Uphold all that is good in me. Uphold all that pleases you, God. Restore me to a sense of being where I can carry out the joy of doing your will. Create in me a clean heart.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is our private prayer for Ash Wednesday.</p>

<h4>Let us pray…</h4>

<p>Holy God. Holy, mighty and immortal God: May I keep a Holy Lent this year. May I let you work in me to create, renew, restore and uphold me so that the fruits of your Spirit may blossom and grow in my life. Amen.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/day-1-ash-wednesday/">Day 1 (Ash Wednesday)</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Introduction to Lent]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/introduction-to-lent/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/introduction-to-lent/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 02:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <pre><code>     Lent (Anglo-Saxon :spring) is the time when we prepare to
</code></pre>

<p>celebrate the great festival of Easter.  At first, the custom of fasting<br>
prior to Easter, taken from the Passover observance, lasted only for a<br>
day or two.  Over centuries, fasting, penance, acts of charity, works of<br>
love and prayer were extended to the forty days before Easter excluding<br>
Sundays.  Lent reminds us of the three great 40-day fasts recorded in<br>
the Bible: Moses on Mount Sinai (Exodus 34:28), Elijah’s journey to<br>
Mount Horeb (1 Kings 19:1-9) and Jesus’ temptation in the wilderness<br>
(Mark 1:13 and parallels).</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/introduction-to-lent/">Introduction to Lent</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Star Runner]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/star-runner/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/star-runner/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h2>#About Star Runner</h2>

<p>Star Runner is an unfinished novel I began back in early 2007. Over the intervening years I have edited and re-edited the first chapter. But all my attempts to both finish the novel and tame it into a believable story have failed.</p>

<p>This might be a recipe for disaster, but other novels have emerged during National Novel Writing Month. I have not wanted to “publish” (and I use this verb very loosely) these books because the beginning story is not finished.</p>

<p>One of the ideas I have entertained over the past couple of years is to turn Star Runner’s introduction into a shorter work, a novel, a novelette or even a short story. I haven’t made any progress here either.</p>

<h3>Alternative Scenario</h3>

<p>Alternatively, I have introduced other recurring characters in the Star Runner universe. One of these is Ronnie Camberwell. I have written several first draft novels where she is the primary character. From time to time Star Runner appears. I could work on these stories and leave Star Runner as a supporting actor, putting off those novels where Star Runner carries the action.</p>

<h3>Thoughts for the Future</h3>

<p>I really want to make some forward progress this year with my fiction writing. I like to think of myself as a writer, but if I don’t have anything suitable for publication, even as an ebook for free download, I may have to abandon the whole idea of being a writer.</p>

<h3>Support</h3>

<p>Of course there is the matter of support. I haven’t found a writer’s group, some firs readers or dare I say it, an editor. Knowing someone I can hire may move this project forward during this upcoming year.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/star-runner/">Star Runner</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[My Idea About This Blog]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/my-idea-about-this-blog/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/my-idea-about-this-blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 23:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>So what is this blog about and why is it here?</p>
<p>I started a little blog on my Raspberry Pi a while back. I used a few different tools, finally selecting <a href="http://www.getnikola.com/">Nikola</a>. That worked well for a while, but I’m not on Linux on a laptop right now and it’s a lot of leg work to keep up. The charm has worn off.</p>
<p>Recently, I bought a MacBook and discovered Mars Edit. I also discovered I can have a static blog on <a href="https://www.github.com/">github</a>. With <a href="http://www.olai.in/">Olai</a>, I can use Mars Edit and push this content to <a href="https://www.github.com/">github</a>. Not a lot of leg work involved.</p>
<p>I can’t customize anything, so that’s why you’re seeing titles and you must click a link to read the articles. I suppose this makes sense in a mobile world with band width caps.</p>

<p>I don’t know right now what I will do with my existing content. I may just repost it with newer dates. It will give me a chance to play with Mars Edit and review what I have written and do a bit of weeding.</p>
<p>Going forward, this blog will be my place to write about anything which interests me. I find writing blog posts is a way for me to keep notes and perhaps these notes will be useful to others.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/my-idea-about-this-blog/">My Idea About This Blog</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/hello-world/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/hello-world/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 23:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Here is my compulsory first post, so Howdy! How ya doing?</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/hello-world/">Hello World!</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[WV]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/wv/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/wv/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Today I installed <code>wv</code> at <a href="http://tim.thechases.com/">Tim Chase&rsquo;s</a><br>
suggestion. It can convert Microsoft word documents into several<br>
formats. Unfortunately, rst is not one of them. However, I used it to<br>
convert a word document into text and then included that text document<br>
into a story for my <a href="http://lajefa.net/">http://lajefa.net/</a> web site. It was pretty<br>
straight forward though all the paragraphs were indented. Thank goodness<br>
for global search and replace.</p>

<p>The command I used was <code>wvText</code> followed by the word document filename.<br>
<code>wvText</code> did the rest.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/wv/">WV</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Day 2]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/day-2/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/day-2/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>Tear Your Heart</h3>

<h4>Reading</h4>

<p>Joel 2: 1-2, 12-17.</p>

<h4>Tear Your Heart</h4>

<p>Joel is calling upon the authorities in the temple to declare a national fast. I suspect, here in the United States where I live, such a thing would never happen. Instead, the President would proclaim a National Day of Prayer.</p>

<p>Either way, Joel is asking everyone to focus their attention because apparently there has been some sort of national disaster. Scholars differ whether an army has attacked and Joel compares it to a swarm of locusts, or whether a swarm of locusts have attacked and Joel compares it to a marauding army. Either way there is a catastrophe.</p>

<p>In the Bible, fasting is seen as a way to indicate to God ones sorrow over ones wrongdoing. In this case the national fast is to say that the nation itself, the people individually and collectively, have displeased God and therefore are trying to put things right between themselves and God.</p>

<p>Like any external activity that we do, we can do it in a way that just touches us on the outside. Fasting and tearing our garments is a sign of distress and grief. Joel however calls upon the people to not only refrain from eating and drinking but to weep, mourn and return to God, to tear their hearts rather than their clothes. In this sense, and we will see this in the next two days in other readings that we have about fasting, fasting is more than refraining from food. Fasting requires a change of heart, hence the tearing of ones heart.</p>

<p>The intent is not deprivation. Surely, with this famine upon the land, there is already deprivation. So it&rsquo;s not physical deprivation that will change anything; it is rather a means to get at the heart of each person.</p>

<p>If the prophet’s plea is for us to get at our own hearts right now:</p>

<ul>
<li>What is it that we need to fast from? * What do we need to tear our hearts about? * How do we go about returning to God and returning to God&rsquo;s ways?<br></li>
</ul>

<h4>Let us pray…</h4>

<p>Oh God, during this Lenten season may you continually invite us to return to you and to learn more deeply how to walk by your Spirit. Amen.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/day-2/">Day 2</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
</channel>
</rss>
