<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Rill Online</title>
  <description><![CDATA[Rill&#39;s Ramblings]]></description>
  <link>http://rillonline.github.io</link>
  <generator>http://www.olai.in</generator>
  <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:10:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <atom:link href="http://rillonline.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Star Runner]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/star-runner/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/star-runner/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h2>#About Star Runner</h2>

<p>Star Runner is an unfinished novel I began back in early 2007. Over the intervening years I have edited and re-edited the first chapter. But all my attempts to both finish the novel and tame it into a believable story have failed.</p>

<p>This might be a recipe for disaster, but other novels have emerged during National Novel Writing Month. I have not wanted to “publish” (and I use this verb very loosely) these books because the beginning story is not finished.</p>

<p>One of the ideas I have entertained over the past couple of years is to turn Star Runner’s introduction into a shorter work, a novel, a novelette or even a short story. I haven’t made any progress here either.</p>

<h3>Alternative Scenario</h3>

<p>Alternatively, I have introduced other recurring characters in the Star Runner universe. One of these is Ronnie Camberwell. I have written several first draft novels where she is the primary character. From time to time Star Runner appears. I could work on these stories and leave Star Runner as a supporting actor, putting off those novels where Star Runner carries the action.</p>

<h3>Thoughts for the Future</h3>

<p>I really want to make some forward progress this year with my fiction writing. I like to think of myself as a writer, but if I don’t have anything suitable for publication, even as an ebook for free download, I may have to abandon the whole idea of being a writer.</p>

<h3>Support</h3>

<p>Of course there is the matter of support. I haven’t found a writer’s group, some firs readers or dare I say it, an editor. Knowing someone I can hire may move this project forward during this upcoming year.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/star-runner/">Star Runner</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[My Idea About This Blog]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/my-idea-about-this-blog/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/my-idea-about-this-blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 23:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>So what is this blog about and why is it here?</p>
<p>I started a little blog on my Raspberry Pi a while back. I used a few different tools, finally selecting <a href="http://www.getnikola.com/">Nikola</a>. That worked well for a while, but I’m not on Linux on a laptop right now and it’s a lot of leg work to keep up. The charm has worn off.</p>
<p>Recently, I bought a MacBook and discovered Mars Edit. I also discovered I can have a static blog on <a href="https://www.github.com/">github</a>. With <a href="http://www.olai.in/">Olai</a>, I can use Mars Edit and push this content to <a href="https://www.github.com/">github</a>. Not a lot of leg work involved.</p>
<p>I can’t customize anything, so that’s why you’re seeing titles and you must click a link to read the articles. I suppose this makes sense in a mobile world with band width caps.</p>

<p>I don’t know right now what I will do with my existing content. I may just repost it with newer dates. It will give me a chance to play with Mars Edit and review what I have written and do a bit of weeding.</p>
<p>Going forward, this blog will be my place to write about anything which interests me. I find writing blog posts is a way for me to keep notes and perhaps these notes will be useful to others.</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/my-idea-about-this-blog/">My Idea About This Blog</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
      <link>http://rillonline.github.io/hello-world/</link>
      <guid>http://rillonline.github.io/hello-world/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 23:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Here is my compulsory first post, so Howdy! How ya doing?</p>

        <a href="http://rillonline.github.io/hello-world/">Hello World!</a>
          was written by <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill</a> at <a href="http://rillonline.github.io">Rill Online</a>. Got a comment? <a href="http://twitter.com/jjude">Tweet</a> it.
      ]]></description>
      <dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator>
    </item>
  
</channel>
</rss>
