<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description>Rill's blog and other writings.</description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 01:50:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Using Flyspell and Emacspeak</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/16/using-flyspell-and-emacspeak/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div id="outline-container-org9a5fb40" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org9a5fb40"&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org9a5fb40"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I didn't have a great set up for spellchecking in Emacs. Ispell works,
but often there are too many choices and Emacspeak does not read them
out. So I investigated Flyspell and now I have a working solution.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3214eee" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3214eee"&gt;The Hook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3214eee"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I now have flyspell working in all text and text-derived buffers by
adding this hook:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
(add-hook 'text-mode-hook 'flyspell-mode)
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This can be disabled in specific circumstances if needed but this is
beyond the scope of this article.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3740dae" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3740dae"&gt;Procedure to Correct Words in a Buffer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3740dae"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are keybindings to autocorrect in &lt;code&gt;flyspell&lt;/code&gt;, but this is not
always advisable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I needed to be able to scroll through the many options. &lt;code&gt;Ispell&lt;/code&gt; gives
choices with numbers, but often there are too many to give you the
list. By putting the following command in my &lt;code&gt;init.el&lt;/code&gt; file via the
customization menus, I am now able to use &lt;code&gt;flyspell&lt;/code&gt; to cursor up and
down a list until I find the right choice. After that, I can just hit return.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If auditory icons is turned on and you are using the default theme,
you will hear something like a rattling sound when you misspell a word. To
correct the word immediately,
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;move point to the misspelled word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press c-c $. (control plus c then s plus 4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emacspeak will say menu. You can use your cursor keys to scroll up
and down the list of suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press return on your selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As well as misspelled word suggestions, you can save your word in a
personal dictionary, accept your spelling for this session or accept
all misspelled words in the buffer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3c931c9" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3c931c9"&gt;Spellchecking the Buffer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3c931c9"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
c-, (control plus comma) can move point from misspelled word to
misspelled word in your buffer. Press c-c $ to correct each one. c-,
will announce when you reach the end of the buffer. Press c-, again to
move to the beginning of the buffer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org503aa9f" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org503aa9f"&gt;Automatic Correction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org503aa9f"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are other commands which can move point and automatically
correct your misspellings. Since this is automatic, the first choice
may not be the correct one. Once the word has been corrected, you will
need to reread your work to find it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org629b375" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org629b375"&gt;Tip&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org629b375"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When moving from misspelled word to misspelled word in your buffer,
Emacspeak will not read out the new misspelled word. Press c-e w to
hear the word. Press c-e w again to have it spelled.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/16/using-flyspell-and-emacspeak/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 02:46:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thinking About the Vine</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/15/thinking-about-the-vine/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I don't know that I am going to write a proper flash sermon on this,
but I can't help thinking about the vineyard in Isaiah 5 and Psalm 80.
They are the assigned texts for the Revised Common Lectionary for
Track 1 Year C.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have read these texts often since I usually review them for John 15
"I am the vine and you are the branches".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One of the things that continues to surprise me while reading the
parable in Isaiah 5 is the violence of God's actions:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking away its hedge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making it a wasteland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not providing any rain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In some translations, there is a distinction between grapes and bad
fruit. A better way to think of this  is cultivated grapes and wild
grapes.. Some translations maintain this distinction which is helpful.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The plantings, the vines, are identified as the people. Their crop is
not the tasty grapes but the wild grapes of oppression and injustice.
That is what is making God angry.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here God is saying that God created an environment for justice and
freedom. Instead, God finds an environment of injustice and, in some
translations, bloodshed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The parable begins with the writer saying that he or she is singing a
song to his/her beloved. The singer is on the side of justice and
righteousness along with God, but as prophet, he/she is pointing out
the state of the people as God sees them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
These chapters we have been reading as part of the lectionary really
point out God's frustration at the people who claim to worship God but
behave counter to God's intentions for humanity.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/15/thinking-about-the-vine/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 15:36:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On Toni Morrison</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/08/on-toni-morrison/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
It was Toni Morrison who taught me that I always assume people are
white in literature and conversation when they could just as easily be
something else.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Writers</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/08/on-toni-morrison/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 01:36:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nick was funny</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/nick-was-funny/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Nick was so funny at dinnertime. I got out his harness. He went into
the bathroom to get a drink but there wasn't much water in the dish. I
hung his harness and leash on the door and filled up his water bowl,
encouraging him to drink some more. He danced around, not sure what to
do. He went into the bathroom but then came out again. Again I
encouraged him to drink but he started butting my legs with his head.
He seemed to be saying, Let's go, so I put his harness on him and off
we went to park.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Nick</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/nick-was-funny/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 22:48:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Psalm 64</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/psalm-64/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have been trying to read a psalm every day. My Old Testament
professor Dr. Robinson said it would change my life. He said that
twenty years ago (that's a scary thought in and of itself). I've never
succeeded at doing this, but it's never too late to give it a shot. I
would read all the psalms twice through in one year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I've been suggesting we read a psalm at the end of our Bible study on
Thursdays. I don't do it every week, but it turns out one of the
participants doesn't like the psalms. I realized that reading one
every week allows us to work through all 150 psalms over time (three
years or so) without getting bogged down in the book of psalms. That
would make things easier for the participant who doesn't like them.
Someone is marking them off as we go.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is a long introduction to reading Psalm 64. I started at Psalm 61
because that is the psalm we read last Thursday and it seemed to be a
good place to start. The problem of embarking on such a task is that
I've read Psalm 1 a lot and never gotten very far after that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I can't remember ever reading Psalm 64 before. No doubt I have, but
nothing stood out to mean. This morning, however, in the wake of the
terrible shootings at El Paso and Youngstown, I couldn't help thinking of
all those bullets or, as the psalmist put it, arrows. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
David is talking about words, not literal weapons, but it doesn't much matter in the
context of the psalm. Behind the bullets were evil words. And evil
words and hatred are at the crux of the problem in this country. It
there weren't so many evil words flying about like arrows, people
shopping on a Saturday morning for school supplies or going out for a
fun-filled evening wouldn't be dead–terrible! Unspeakable evil!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I take comfort in verse 8:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="verse"&gt;
Their own tongues shall ruin them.&lt;br&gt;
All who see them will shake their heads.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://worldenglishbible.org"&gt;World English Bible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Reflection</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/psalm-64/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 20:07:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mammoth Book of More Historical Whodunnits</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/04/the-mammoth-book-of-more-historical-whodunnits/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
This is a collection of short stories. This gave me hours of enjoyment
and I discovered many new authors. I was delighted to read the first
story by Steven Saylor about Gordianus the Fixer. Check it out at
&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/381433.The_Mammoth_Book_of_More_Historical_Whodunnits"&gt;Good
Reads&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/04/the-mammoth-book-of-more-historical-whodunnits/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 02:38:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Library</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/28/in-the-library/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Picture this. Ronnie, our intrepid heroine, is
sitting in the great library of the wizards in the heart of Magic
City. (I know. I know. These names are not very imaginative and need
changing, but it is the best I can do right now.) Anyway, she is
sitting in the library not because she wants to be there but because
she is compelled to be there. The Tribunal of All Wizards (Is this a
better name?) has sentenced her to serve there for some unspecified
length of time. She goes to the library at the pleasure of the Grand
Mistress of Wizards who doesn't like her to begin with. Ronnie is
fulfilling her sentence for the misuse of magic which caused the death
of her mentor, Grand Master Awk.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Although Ronnie is unhappy that she must remain in the Magic Lands for
perhaps the rest of her life, she makes the best of being confined to
the library and her living quarters for most of every day. As
imprisonments go in the inhabited galaxy, it is a very lenient
sentence.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The wizards did not come up with this punishment without
reason. Ronnie has shown an aptitude for magic. The wizards hope she
can learn to read and understand the books stored in the library which
they cannot even open. Ronnie thinks their hope in her is
misplaced. Even if she can open a book, why do they think she can read
an ancient script and make sense of it. She does not possess these
skills.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Neverthe less, she goes to the library and tries to open every book on
every shelf. There are many thousands of books.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then one day Ronnie lugs a very large volume to the library table by
the window. It has a pleasant view of a garden. She sets the tome
down. What else can she possibly call the book but a tome. It is
dusty. Its binding shows much wear. She wonders just how old this book
is and what sort of a book this is. There are no pictures on the
covers. The script on its binding is beautiful and perhaps contains
grains of precious gems. This is not her expertise either but the
script seems to sparkle.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
With no expectations at all, she tries to open the book. And it
opens.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ronnie gasps. The librarian, working at his desk across the room,
looks up to see the book open and hurries over.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Can you read it?" he asks rather breathlessly.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Can you see the pictures?" Ronnie asks him.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"The page is blank," the librarian responds, puzzled.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"No, it is not," Ronnie says. "It is a beautifully done star chart."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
They stand in silence. Ronnie can see it while the librarian cannot.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"A star chart of what?" the librarian finally asks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"I don't know," Ronnie says. "I would need a modern star chart and a
way to evaluate procession and drift. I don't recognize any of these
stars, but I am not from around this part of the galactic arm. The
constellations look all wrong to me."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Can you copy the chart?" the librarian asks quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Let's see if I can," Ronnie says.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then she smiles. "If this is a map to treasure, I claim it by virtue
of being able to read the map."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The librarian does not see the humor in her claim but hurries away to
get paper and writing implements. He also calls the Grand Mistress and
she comes to hover over Ronnie's shoulder.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After Ronnie's crude representation of the beautiful chart and much
discussion, the Tribunal corrects the star chart for this time
period. They show it to Ronnie.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"It's Planet X," she says, pointing to a particular
constellation. I've been there."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In an earlier unpublished adventure, she and Captain Star Runner visited this
forbidden planet with disastrous results. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/28/in-the-library/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 01:23:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More Thoughts on Amos 7</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/12/more-thoughts-on-amos-7/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Jeroboam II had a 40-year reign. During that time, the country
prospered. Reading through the Book of Amos, it is clear that only
some were doing well. Granted, Amos was from Judah and the Lord
sent him. Setting aside the question of worshiping God outside of
Jerusalem and the synchronistic character of temple worship in Israel,
Amos inveighs against personal excess and unethical business
practices. Israel is rotten at its core, straying far from the
precepts God has prescribed for the people in their interpersonal
relationships and societal responsibilities for the poor and needy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It is astounding that twenty-five years after Jeroboam II's death,
Israel fell to the Assyrians. Assyria forcibly deported many to the
far reaches of its empire, effectively dispersing Israel's people so
that ethnic and religious identity of the people evaporated as they
were absorbed by other cultures and religions. Although the land
remained, Israel and its people were absolutely gone except in
the prophetic imagination.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What makes reading Amos so disturbing are the parallels to our own
country and culture. How close to annihilation are we? Could life as
we know it come tumbling down as quickly as it did for the people of
Israel?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Who will stand up and prophesy to the people and will anyone believe
God's prophet? Or are we doomed to repeat  the experience of ancient Israel?
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/12/more-thoughts-on-amos-7/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 20:27:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding Good News in Amos and Psalm 82</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/11/finding-good-news-in-amos-and-psalm-82/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
These are the Hebrew Scripture readings for July 14, 2019 in the
United Methodist Church.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I am not preaching, but a friend asked me to find good news in Amos
7:1-17 (the whole chapter). Here's what is going on:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things are going well in Israel. The economy is humming
along. Business is good. There are no imminent threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Israel has set up a variant of worship within its borders, not
supporting, going to or wanting to worship in Jerusalem in the
kingdom of Judah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite the good economy and the absence of threats foreign or
domestic, the poor are suffering. Trickle down economics didn't work
then either and many of them are being cheated when they buy goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God sends Amos, whose name means &lt;i&gt;burden-bbearer&lt;/i&gt; to prophesy.
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amos is from Judah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amos is not a professional prophet. He has not attended prophet
school. (Yes, they had them back then.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amos seems himself as a shepherd and a sycamore tree farmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Common English Bible (2010) agrees with my Old Testament
professor who insisted that Amos speaks about himself in the
present tense. He still tends sheep and fruit trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The word is bad for Israel and particularly Amaniah in this chapter,
but the good news is directed to God's championing the poor. Things
are out of alignment in Israel. That is why God shows Amos the plumb
line. Measure Israel. See how askew it is. It needs to be brought back
to plumb, to act, as Micah puts it, like this: "… to do justly, to love mercy,
and to walk humbly with your God" Micah 6:8b NKJV).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Amos bears the burden of speaking God's word in a foreign country to
hostile audiences. He does it because he is obedient to God's call and
because the people of Israel are God's people, too.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Psalm 82 is subtitled, in my New King James Version of the Bible, &lt;i&gt;An
Appeal to Justice&lt;/i&gt;. When we cannot bring things into plumb, we ask God
to do it. We are confident that God will do it even if it is not on
our time table.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The psalmist says"All the foundations of the earth are unstable"
(Psalm 82:5c NKJV).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the Gospel for Sunday, Jesus shows how the good Samaritan behaves
towards the helpless man and
declares that he has fulfilled the law to love his neighbor as
himself. The Samaritan was able to do this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tend the injured man's wounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring him to the inn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage the innkeeper to continue to care for the injured man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promised to reimburse the innkeeper for any expense above what the
Samaritan had already paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes the fix is beyond our individual or collective ability. Then
we appeal to God for the justice we are unable to deliver.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is not an excuse. It is a reality.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Anaziah and Jeroboam were powerful men.  As such, God  charged them to
care for the poor and needy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
God's charge has not changed. Providing safe and sanitary conditions
for migrants at our southern border is not a political matter. God has
charged us to care for those who are in need and for the sojourner
among us. It is a question of carrying out the will of God–Thy will
be done.   
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/11/finding-good-news-in-amos-and-psalm-82/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 16:28:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>No Camp Nanowrimo This Month</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/04/no-camp-nanowrimo-this-month/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I was going to participate in &lt;a href="https://www.campnanowrimo.org/"&gt;Camp Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; this year. I like bbbsetting a low writing goal and meeting it. Call it childish if you like, but positive reinforcement is fun.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But I wanted to do something more than just write a first draft and so I was leery of making a commitment I couldn't keep. Again, seeing a congratulatory message on my screen is quite satisfying.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's what I really want to do:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit my Kearsarge novel. I wrote it as part of &lt;a href="https://www.nanowrimo.org/"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; some time ago and have never finished an edit. I would like to be able to give it to an editor and create an ebook out of it with a cover and everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish Kearsarge to my &lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; site with each chapter as a separate web page linked together. (Right now, I don't know how to do this. I am refreshing my knowledge of orgmode and learning new features.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish writing my memoir piece on Chance so that Cindy can look it over before I send it off to Joy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have already set up &lt;a href="https://www.getnikola.com/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt; to deploy my blog and associated pages to &lt;a href="https://www.github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/04/no-camp-nanowrimo-this-month/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 15:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>