<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description>Rill's blog and other writings.</description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 16:52:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>January 2</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/02/january-2/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I am reading the Psalms and thinking about goals, Psalm 34
presents three. I will look at them individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will bless the LORD at all times; &lt;br&gt;
his praise shall ever be in my mouth.&lt;br&gt;
Psalm 34:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a strong suit of mine. It is one form of prayer that does
not come naturally to me. 
Blessing and praise are not always my default. I am trying to say
"Have a blessed day" when I leave my bus, but "Thank you" comes far
more naturally. I have tried writing in a gratitude journal, but both
journaling and finding ways to be grateful in a meaningful way is
hard. I could write almost every Wednesday and Thursday: "I am
grateful for my Bible study." and it would cease to be gratitude. It
would be a item to tick off. This would not mean I wasn't grateful. It
would just mean that the gratitude itself would stop being one and
just be what I wrote down for those days. I could probably find a
weekly gratitude for each day and then the exercise would collapse
under its own weight. It is like going around the Thanksgiving table
and people say the same thing every year, a version of "For health and
strength and daily food we praise thy name, O Lord." I want my
blessing and praise to be in the moment. Often my moments are focused
elsewhere, like not falling when I am stepping off the bus or not
losing my sense of direction when walking home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come, children, and listen to me;&lt;br&gt;
I will teach you the fear of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Psalm 34:11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't do this much when I am participating in Bible study or
preaching, but I think it is a worthwhile goal. Thinking of Jesus as
ever present, God with us. Some may argue that Jesus came so that we
might not be afraid of God, of judgment, that Jesus brought us grace,
but we had that already in the Hebrew scriptures. God is slow to anger
and abounding in steadfast love. I think of fear of the Lord as
reverence and acknowledgment of God's presence so I want that
awareness to be closer to me than it currently is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My third selection is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turn from evil and do good;&lt;br&gt;
seek peace and pursue it.&lt;br&gt;
Psalm 34:14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lofty one in the starkness of biblical absolutes. This is
more of a consciousness thing, being aware of when I fail to do good
and when I need to actively seek a more peaceful interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose all three really boil down to this: "I will bless the Lord
at all times."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Biblical Reflection</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/02/january-2/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 16:06:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>January 1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/01/january-1-2020/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read this webpage today. &lt;a href="http://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/Christmas/HolyName_RCL.html"&gt;Holy Name&lt;/a&gt; Without a doubt, the hearer of these texts are to concentrate on the name of Jesus and of all the ways we might engage God's name. But being a more perverse person, that is not where my mind went. In Philippians,Paul says "Let the same mind be in you that was in Christ Jesus." (2:5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? I have read these words many times and have often wondered but never stopped to think about them separately. Yes. Yes. Every knee should bow and all that, but what would it mean to have the same mind as Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is Jesus' servanthood, Jesus' willingness to do God's will, to be God with us rather than God apart from us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I begin the year thinking I might have a goal this year to come back to these readings and be Christ to those I meet. It's been a Christian practice forever, but I forget it all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People get nervous around other people when they start spouting religion or say things like, "Jesus loves you." I am not that sort of person. But I can channel it and act as if I had said it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be mindful of having the mind of Jesus this year. Who knows. It might even become habitual. And isn't that the point of resolutions anyway?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Biblical Reflection</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/01/january-1-2020/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 22:59:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Indentation</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/23/indentation/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have been writing my Nanowrimo Prep document. This is a series of
headings and several nested lists along with lengthy paragraphs either
under a heading or under one of my list items.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This sounds straight forward enough but I have run into problems
largely because I didn't fully grasp how Org thought of indentations.
This was fully revealed to me when I exported my document to html.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I was totally baffled. The web page didn't look like what I was
writing. To solve this, I started editing the html document and
converted back to org using pandoc. The conversion wasn't perfect, but
good enough to clue me in.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Did I mention that actually writing in html is &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; difficult?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you want to see your document as a web page, type:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
c-c c-e h o
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This will not only convert your document, but open it in a web page
where you can easily see what is going on. Using a screen reader, the
headlines are identified as well as the lists, the number of items in
a list and whether you are going into or coming out of a nested list.
Another helpful clue is that the headings are numbered (unless you
have turned this off globally). Finally, the list items are numbered
(if you are using numbered lists) and you can see how Org is thinking
of them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Indent Everything&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, maybe not everything, but even paragraphs under a heading or a
list item should be indented to see the relationship.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes Org resisted this. I had a paragraph at the left hand margin
and I want to shift it left three spaces. Org couldn't do that for me
so I had to manually indent line after line. Auto-fill couldn't do it
either.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If your paragraph is long, Emacspeak will prompt you if you want to
"read this long line?" Annoying, but just press 'n' and then perform
one action. Emacspeak will ask you again. Again press "n" and perform
that action.    
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once you have your paragraph at the right indentation, move to the
beginning of the line and press "m-q" to reflow the paragraph. Now
that pesky "read long line?" prompt will go away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you are moving things around, adding and subtracting list items, go
to the top of the list and press "c-c c-c" to renumber it. This will
maintain your sanity somewhat. It will also show you where the
numbering is inconsistent. At this point, you can track down the
problem in your formatting.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Happy writing. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Org</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/23/indentation/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 15:52:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Allen Palmer</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/22/allen-palmer/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
is about the emotional content of the 12 stages I wrote about
earlier. Be sure to check it out. It really helps me understand.
There are other good posts here, too.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/22/allen-palmer/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 23:12:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nanowrimo Prep</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/22/nanowrimo-prep/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.nanowrimo.org"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; doesn't start until November 1, but an email dropped into my
inbox about Nanowrimo prep. I started reading over the
&lt;a href="https://preview.nanowrimo.org/nano-prep-101"&gt;material&lt;/a&gt; I began to sketch out my novel.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I realized I needed more information so I started reading Blake
Snyder's &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49464.Save_the_Cat"&gt;Save the Cat: The Last Book on Screenwriting You'll Ever Need&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I know, it's about screenwriting but it is applicable to
novel writing, too. I also consulted Jessica Brody's &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/32805475-save-the-cat-writes-a-novel"&gt; Save the Cat!
Writes a Novel&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I realized very quickly I did not have enough information to plot my
novel. I know the beginning and the ending, but I had no idea what
happens in the middle. And the middle is 60% of the novel. The ending
is clear, but not how the middle ends and how the ending begins.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Instead I realized I needed to go back to a project I started putting
together in 2015. I call this novel the Three Laws of Magic. I am
focusing on only one law of magic here: With great power comes great
responsibility. This will be familiar to those of you who use &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;
on your Linux machines. I am still not sure if the other admonishments
work here or not.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The novel I have set aside is clearly the third book in the series and
perhaps my experiments with &lt;i&gt;The Wizard of Marling&lt;/i&gt; is the second
book.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's how I know &lt;i&gt;Mulberry Bend&lt;/i&gt; is the third novel.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In Brody's book, she lists ten universal lessons:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness: of self or of others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love: includes self-love, family love, romantic love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceptance: of self, of circumstances, of reality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith: in oneself, in others, in the world, in God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear: overcoming it, conquering it, finding courage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust: in oneself, in others, in the unknown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival: including the will to live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selflessness: including sacrifice, altruism, heroism, and overcoming greed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsibility: including duty, standing up for a cause, accepting one’s destiny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redemption: including atonement, accepting blame, remorse, and salvation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I know &lt;i&gt;Mulberry Bend&lt;/i&gt; is acceptance. I tried putting this with &lt;i&gt;The
Three Laws of Magic&lt;/i&gt; and I realized my protagonist doesn't accept who
she is at the end. So I looked through the list and came to the
conclusion that her growth point is responsibility. This is not as
great a leap for Ronnie Camberwell as acceptance will be. As I said, I
have no idea what book two will require.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Having spent time with the 15 "beats" of &lt;i&gt;Save the Cat&lt;/i&gt;, I decided
this structure didn't fit my novel as well as my original structure as
laid out by Christopher Bogler in &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/173302.The_Writer_s_Journey"&gt; The Writer's Journey: Mythic
Structure for Writers&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
All of these books are based on Joseph Campbell's &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/588138.The_Hero_With_a_Thousand_Faces"&gt; The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/a&gt; which he published in 1949. Campbell posits that all stories from
all around the world have the same structure regardless of their
genre. As listeners, readers or watchers of story, we find this
structure satisfying.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I've never been a plotter, but since I have had trouble writing this
novel in a general sort of way, I decided to try structure this time.
Stay tuned. There will be more as I proceed.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/22/nanowrimo-prep/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 20:48:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Story Idea for Nanowrimo</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/17/story-idea-for-nanowrimo/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href="https://preview.nanowrimo.org/"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; Prep email arrived in my inbox last week or maybe
earlier. I opened it up to find I have access to an entire workbook
and a weekly schedule to get ready. I've been going through the
document. Sadly many of the links were eight broken or not even inside
the pdf. Nevertheless, there's enough there to get started.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I haven't been able to write the story of Ronnie Camberwell arriving
in the Magic Lands and how she got stuck there. Perhaps it is one of
those stories that can eluded to but never written. I remember
that Rumpole had such a story.. Eventually John Mortimer wrote it and
it was so disappointing. It worked so much better when Rumpole
referenced it but kept the details foggy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Working under this idea, I have decided to write a different story
while Ronnie is confined. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's my outline so far.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org33ee754" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="initial-idea"&gt;&lt;a id="org33ee754"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Initial Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-initial-idea"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The novel is called Mulberry Bend, A Ronnie Camberwell Novel&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It takes place after The Three Laws of Magic&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It takes place in the capital city of the Magic Lands.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To the uninitiated, the city appears to be a medieval city. To Ronnie,
it is a city with very extremes of well-being.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In a very poor area called Five Points, there is a winding street
called Mulberry Bend.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The mystery centers in this area and on this street.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org0c4889f" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org0c4889f"&gt;I read a prompt recently about a lost girl.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org0c4889f"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The lost girl ends up in this section of the city. (This is based on
the 19th century area of New York City.) Tripp and Ronnie set out to find her. Explores the relationship between Tripp and Ronnie and is Ronnie's first trip outside of the wizard compound. Ronnie is restricted to the city. Tripp is still sexually attracted to Ronnie. Ronnie is conflicted, wanting Tripp but also tied to the absent Captain Star Runner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org69e7d56" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org69e7d56"&gt;Some ideas about the lost girl:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org69e7d56"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Tigerfu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not from the capital city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Mistress Luna is very anxious that the girl be found so the
wizards reputation does not suffer but she is not invested in the
girl at all. Ronnie is appalled. Tripp is philosophical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The leader of the field trip is anxious that her reputation will
suffer if the lost girl is not found, but she is not really
invested in the girl either. Ronnie presses her to
understand. The girl is mute and her guardian merely wants the
girl off her hands. It seems everyone has this attitude. With
four hands, Ronnie can't figure out why the girl cannot sign and
make herself understood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tripp explains the Tigerfu in this part of the Confederacy is not
particularly sympathetic to disabilities. It's a very frontier
mentality and everyone has to pull their own weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ronnie has to rethink her idea about the Tigerfu and their
openness. Why doesn't this girl get any help. Can her disability
be mitigated? The Tigerfu are very advanced with surgery and
psychology. Can the girl speak and chooses not to because of
trauma or is she physically unable to speak?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ronnie checks the library catalog. Muteness is covered in the
catalog. From the entry, Ronnie believes the ancient wizards knew
something about it but she has not delved deeply enough into
reading the library volumes on these subjects to be fluent enough
to read the texts easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org08fda19" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org08fda19"&gt;The Rest of the Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org08fda19"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So I have the opening of the story but not what Tripp and Ronnie find
in Five Points. I don't know what becomes of the lost girl. Stay tuned!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfcb2cce" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgfcb2cce"&gt;Where is Ronnie in Her Life When All is Said and Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgfcb2cce"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don't know how Ronnie grows in this story and how her relationship
with the Tribunal of Wizards is changed. I've had a sense for some
time that Ronnie will eventually become the Grand Mistress and will
choose to stay, providing leadership for this collections of worlds
within the Tigerfu Confederacy. Her travel ban will be lifted so that
future adventures may occur elsewhere. But that is in the future and will not be realized in this novel.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Nanowrimo</category><category>Ronnie Camberwell</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/17/story-idea-for-nanowrimo/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 18:05:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Writing a Book Part 1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have started to write a book which gathers together some of my
previous posts on Org and then fleshes out the material.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org524d430" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org524d430"&gt;Setting Up a To-do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org524d430"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I first set up a to-do to track my progress. I am modifying the steps
as I go, but here is what it currently looks like:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
* STARTED Write a series of articles on getting organized with org mode [5/10]

     1. [X] Gather all files into a new git repository
     2. [X] Create a landing page for the ebook
     3. [X] Write an outline for my getting organized articles
     4. [X] Integrate blog posts into this outline
     5. [X] Write a script to convert .org files to .md files and copy
        them to the book directory
     6. [ ] Write the book. Chapter by Chapter goes below.
     7. [ ] Publish the ebook
     8. [ ] Upload the ebook to archive.org
     9. [ ] Update the download link on the landing page.
     10. [ ] Write a blog post announcing the book.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have checked off have of the items, but it is the easy stuff I've
checked off. So far I only have listed one items for writing the book
though I plan on adding check boxes underneath this item so I can
check off each chapter. The final check box is to review the entire
book and make any necessary corrections.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"STARTED" is a to-do state that I developed for my projects. More on
that when I discuss "TODO" in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org0fe9fe6" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org0fe9fe6"&gt;Setting Things Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org0fe9fe6"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up the git repository was very straight forward on &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.
Then I looked over my blog and copied the posts that applied into
that directory and updated the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I then wrote a landing page for the book. The idea of a landing page
is to have the potential reader focus on your book and the &lt;b&gt;Call to
Action&lt;/b&gt; which is for you, the reader, to click on the "buy" button.
My page is quite simple and does not have a "Download" button yet
since the book is not finished. You can look at it &lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/living-my-life-in-plain-text-page.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3d00dd0" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3d00dd0"&gt;Outlining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3d00dd0"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I then set about putting together an outline to help me think about
what the book should cover. This is not set in stone. More chapters
may appear and the ones listed here may disappear. This is what it
currently looks like in Org markup.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** Table of Contents
** Introduction -- what this book hopes to accomplish
** Thinking About Doing
** A Few Quick Notes on Orgmode Markup
** Setting up your Initial Emacs Configuration for Org
** Setting up a Calendar
** Seeing Your Calendar as an Agenda
** Making a To-do List
** How Deep Should You Go?
*** To-do Checkboxes
*** To-do Keywords
*** Priorities
** Revisiting the Agenda
*** Helpful keys in the Agenda -- archiving, saving, changing status
*** Seeing the Agenda on STartup
*** Remember to Refresh
** Capturing Information
*** Deciding what to Capture
** To Refile or Not to Refile
** Writing in Orgmode
** Exporting and Publishing in Orgmode
** Keeping Track of Expenses
** References
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org7542d41" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org7542d41"&gt;Promotion and Demotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org7542d41"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In looking this over, the first thing I want to do is change the
headline level. I need to move everything up one level so that heading
3s become heading2s and heading2s become heading1s
What I want to do is called promotion. I highlighted the text, went to
the org menu and found "promote" under the "edit structure" menu item.
There is a shortcut key you can use if you do this often enough to
remember it "m-s-left". You can also demote items "m-s-right"..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org9330537" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org9330537"&gt;Changing Headlines into Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org9330537"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can change headlines into lists and lists into headlines. I
changed my outline headings into an unordered list of to-do items by
highlighting them and then applying the command "c-c -". That's "c-c
hyphen". The "-" (hyphen) gives you the clue. The asterisks "*" are
replaced wit a hyphen "-". You can go the other way by using "c-c *" (asterisk).  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orge7e03ea" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orge7e03ea"&gt;Making an Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orge7e03ea"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orge78c6d3" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orge78c6d3"&gt;What Didn't Work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orge78c6d3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then I investigated how to make an epub. Pandoc can do this. One of
the examples I found showed how to put a bunch of markdown files in a
directory and then turn them into an ebook. Great, I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I tried to use org-publish to do this but I could not get a batch
transformation of all org files. I've tried this in the past and the
markdown export function still hangs. I think I had 30 buffers open wantiiting
for something. I have no idea what   
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I found this script on the &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org/faqs.html"&gt;pandoc site&lt;/a&gt; and modified it for my purpose:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
#!/bin/bash
# Convert all org files in a directory to markdown
# This script is to convert and move markdown into the book folder

for f in *.org;
do pandoc "$f" -s -o "${f%.org}.md";
done
mv *.md book/
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then I discovered I would have to include every filename in the
directory in my pandoc command. That seemed more trouble than it was
worth as the moment so I will just write in one file and perhaps split
it out at the end so that I can update it more easily. We'll see.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org66ebbf8" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org66ebbf8"&gt;What Did work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org66ebbf8"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had to add some YML stuff to the beginning of my file:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
---
title: Living My Life in Plain Text
author: Rill Woolnough
rights: Creative Commons Attribution Non-commercial ShareAlike
---
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's the pandoc command I am using:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
pandoc -o book.epub book.org --toc --toc-depth=3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org568499d" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org568499d"&gt;Reading the Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org568499d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So how to read it? Enter emacspeak. It uses the eww browser to render
the book. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
m-x     emacspeak-epub-open  ret
enter the path to the book ret
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Because Firefox is my default browser, the book opens there. There is
single letter navigation to move around in the book as if you are in a
regular web page. alt-f4 closes the book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3191d93" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3191d93"&gt;Back to Work!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3191d93"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now I'm going back to writing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Org</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 17:17:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>org-sort-list</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/09/org-sort-list/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
After sorting my lines using &lt;code&gt;m-x sort-lines&lt;/code&gt;, I have discovered org
itself has a sorting lines function. Here's how to use it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight the list you want to sort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;c-c ^&lt;/code&gt; (carat or s=6).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You will be prompted to indicate what kind of a sort you want.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a for alphabetical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f for function which I will not cover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;n for numeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x for checkboxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If these letters are capitalized, reverse order is used.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That's it. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/09/org-sort-list/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:15:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I Miss Her</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/06/i-miss-her/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I must have written this in the fall of 2006. Caitlin, my first
Seeing Eye dog, died on July 10, 2006. Elwood did not come into my
life until November 27th. I always remember Caitlin, my chocolate
Lab, on her birthday, September 6, 1992. Thinking about her still
brings tears to my eyes and a lump in my throat.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org8f020af" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org8f020af"&gt;I miss her&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org8f020af"&gt;
&lt;p class="verse"&gt;
In the daily tasks,&lt;br&gt;
in the ordinary doing of things,&lt;br&gt;
I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
25minutes to an appointment–&lt;br&gt;
I will take her out. There is time for that.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
I will sit  in my chair. She will come to be petted, to ask for a biscuit.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
I lay down in bed at night and listen for her breathing by the foot of the bed.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
I awake in the morning and check the time. I will dress and take her out.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
Her water bowl is no longer on the floor under the dishwasher door when I load and unload.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/06/i-miss-her/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 18:44:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Turning Off Auto-fill-mode in a Single Buffer</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/04/turning-off-auto-fill-mode-in-a-single-buffer/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
In my article on
&lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/02/using-checkboxes/"&gt;Using Checkboxes&lt;/a&gt; I discussed sorting lines in my ideas file. I went ahead
and added more ideas to the file. Because I sometimes forget details,
I decided to include many details in several entries.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Details are good, right? Well, not if they wrap to another line. This
messes up sorting since the sort doesn't know how to keep the
additional lines with their starting line. I knew that, but hoped
(unreasonably) that everything would stay together. Of course, it
didn't. So I had to look for a solution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The problem is simple enough. Auto-fill-mode is turned on by default.
In general, auto-fill-mode is a good thing. When the line gets too
long, Emacs inserts a line break and a new line is started. Happily,
when typing in org-mode as I was, Org appropriately wraps the line with a
two space indentation. Org knows my additional words belong to this
list item. HTML will know it, too, because Org will tell it by
enclosing the whole thing in "&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;" tags. But sort-lines is
emphatic that a line is a line.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The solution, not surprisingly, is to turn off auto-fill-mode in this
buffer. But how? I started searching for the answer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The readily available answer was this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
m-x auto-fill-mode
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This toggles auto-fill-mode on and off. If it is on to begin with, all
I have to do is toggle it off when I open the file and life is good.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Except … well, except that I want to write ideas with long
explanations because I forget. And it is &lt;b&gt;very&lt;/b&gt; likely I will forget
to do this.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Allthough it took some time, I finally found a way to do this so
auto-fill-mode would be turned off for the buffer and I don't have to
remember what to do.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I placed the following line at the top of my ideas file:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
;; -*- mode: org; mode: auto-fill -1; -*-
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I refresh the current buffer via the Org menu and autofilling stopped.
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: I did find I had to use "-1" rather than "0" to turn off
auto-fill.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Edited 2019-09-07. I originally had the mode as text when it should be org. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/04/turning-off-auto-fill-mode-in-a-single-buffer/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 18:56:46 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>