<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description>Rill's blog and other writings.</description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 21:33:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Nanowrimo Prep</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/22/nanowrimo-prep/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.nanowrimo.org"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; doesn't start until November 1, but an email dropped into my
inbox about Nanowrimo prep. I started reading over the
&lt;a href="https://preview.nanowrimo.org/nano-prep-101"&gt;material&lt;/a&gt; I began to sketch out my novel.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I realized I needed more information so I started reading Blake
Snyder's &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49464.Save_the_Cat"&gt;Save the Cat: The Last Book on Screenwriting You'll Ever Need&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I know, it's about screenwriting but it is applicable to
novel writing, too. I also consulted Jessica Brody's &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/32805475-save-the-cat-writes-a-novel"&gt; Save the Cat!
Writes a Novel&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I realized very quickly I did not have enough information to plot my
novel. I know the beginning and the ending, but I had no idea what
happens in the middle. And the middle is 60% of the novel. The ending
is clear, but not how the middle ends and how the ending begins.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Instead I realized I needed to go back to a project I started putting
together in 2015. I call this novel the Three Laws of Magic. I am
focusing on only one law of magic here: With great power comes great
responsibility. This will be familiar to those of you who use &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;
on your Linux machines. I am still not sure if the other admonishments
work here or not.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The novel I have set aside is clearly the third book in the series and
perhaps my experiments with &lt;i&gt;The Wizard of Marling&lt;/i&gt; is the second
book.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's how I know &lt;i&gt;Mulberry Bend&lt;/i&gt; is the third novel.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In Brody's book, she lists ten universal lessons:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness: of self or of others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love: includes self-love, family love, romantic love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceptance: of self, of circumstances, of reality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith: in oneself, in others, in the world, in God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear: overcoming it, conquering it, finding courage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust: in oneself, in others, in the unknown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival: including the will to live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selflessness: including sacrifice, altruism, heroism, and overcoming greed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsibility: including duty, standing up for a cause, accepting one’s destiny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redemption: including atonement, accepting blame, remorse, and salvation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I know &lt;i&gt;Mulberry Bend&lt;/i&gt; is acceptance. I tried putting this with &lt;i&gt;The
Three Laws of Magic&lt;/i&gt; and I realized my protagonist doesn't accept who
she is at the end. So I looked through the list and came to the
conclusion that her growth point is responsibility. This is not as
great a leap for Ronnie Camberwell as acceptance will be. As I said, I
have no idea what book two will require.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Having spent time with the 15 "beats" of &lt;i&gt;Save the Cat&lt;/i&gt;, I decided
this structure didn't fit my novel as well as my original structure as
laid out by Christopher Bogler in &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/173302.The_Writer_s_Journey"&gt; The Writer's Journey: Mythic
Structure for Writers&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
All of these books are based on Joseph Campbell's &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/588138.The_Hero_With_a_Thousand_Faces"&gt; The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/a&gt; which he published in 1949. Campbell posits that all stories from
all around the world have the same structure regardless of their
genre. As listeners, readers or watchers of story, we find this
structure satisfying.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I've never been a plotter, but since I have had trouble writing this
novel in a general sort of way, I decided to try structure this time.
Stay tuned. There will be more as I proceed.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/22/nanowrimo-prep/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 20:48:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Story Idea for Nanowrimo</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/17/story-idea-for-nanowrimo/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href="https://preview.nanowrimo.org/"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; Prep email arrived in my inbox last week or maybe
earlier. I opened it up to find I have access to an entire workbook
and a weekly schedule to get ready. I've been going through the
document. Sadly many of the links were eight broken or not even inside
the pdf. Nevertheless, there's enough there to get started.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I haven't been able to write the story of Ronnie Camberwell arriving
in the Magic Lands and how she got stuck there. Perhaps it is one of
those stories that can eluded to but never written. I remember
that Rumpole had such a story.. Eventually John Mortimer wrote it and
it was so disappointing. It worked so much better when Rumpole
referenced it but kept the details foggy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Working under this idea, I have decided to write a different story
while Ronnie is confined. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's my outline so far.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org33ee754" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="initial-idea"&gt;&lt;a id="org33ee754"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Initial Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-initial-idea"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The novel is called Mulberry Bend, A Ronnie Camberwell Novel&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It takes place after The Three Laws of Magic&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It takes place in the capital city of the Magic Lands.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To the uninitiated, the city appears to be a medieval city. To Ronnie,
it is a city with very extremes of well-being.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In a very poor area called Five Points, there is a winding street
called Mulberry Bend.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The mystery centers in this area and on this street.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org0c4889f" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org0c4889f"&gt;I read a prompt recently about a lost girl.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org0c4889f"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The lost girl ends up in this section of the city. (This is based on
the 19th century area of New York City.) Tripp and Ronnie set out to find her. Explores the relationship between Tripp and Ronnie and is Ronnie's first trip outside of the wizard compound. Ronnie is restricted to the city. Tripp is still sexually attracted to Ronnie. Ronnie is conflicted, wanting Tripp but also tied to the absent Captain Star Runner.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org69e7d56" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org69e7d56"&gt;Some ideas about the lost girl:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org69e7d56"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Tigerfu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not from the capital city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Mistress Luna is very anxious that the girl be found so the
wizards reputation does not suffer but she is not invested in the
girl at all. Ronnie is appalled. Tripp is philosophical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The leader of the field trip is anxious that her reputation will
suffer if the lost girl is not found, but she is not really
invested in the girl either. Ronnie presses her to
understand. The girl is mute and her guardian merely wants the
girl off her hands. It seems everyone has this attitude. With
four hands, Ronnie can't figure out why the girl cannot sign and
make herself understood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tripp explains the Tigerfu in this part of the Confederacy is not
particularly sympathetic to disabilities. It's a very frontier
mentality and everyone has to pull their own weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ronnie has to rethink her idea about the Tigerfu and their
openness. Why doesn't this girl get any help. Can her disability
be mitigated? The Tigerfu are very advanced with surgery and
psychology. Can the girl speak and chooses not to because of
trauma or is she physically unable to speak?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ronnie checks the library catalog. Muteness is covered in the
catalog. From the entry, Ronnie believes the ancient wizards knew
something about it but she has not delved deeply enough into
reading the library volumes on these subjects to be fluent enough
to read the texts easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org08fda19" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org08fda19"&gt;The Rest of the Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org08fda19"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So I have the opening of the story but not what Tripp and Ronnie find
in Five Points. I don't know what becomes of the lost girl. Stay tuned!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfcb2cce" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgfcb2cce"&gt;Where is Ronnie in Her Life When All is Said and Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgfcb2cce"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don't know how Ronnie grows in this story and how her relationship
with the Tribunal of Wizards is changed. I've had a sense for some
time that Ronnie will eventually become the Grand Mistress and will
choose to stay, providing leadership for this collections of worlds
within the Tigerfu Confederacy. Her travel ban will be lifted so that
future adventures may occur elsewhere. But that is in the future and will not be realized in this novel.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Nanowrimo</category><category>Ronnie Camberwell</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/17/story-idea-for-nanowrimo/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 18:05:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Writing a Book Part 1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have started to write a book which gathers together some of my
previous posts on Org and then fleshes out the material.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org524d430" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org524d430"&gt;Setting Up a To-do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org524d430"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I first set up a to-do to track my progress. I am modifying the steps
as I go, but here is what it currently looks like:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
* STARTED Write a series of articles on getting organized with org mode [5/10]

     1. [X] Gather all files into a new git repository
     2. [X] Create a landing page for the ebook
     3. [X] Write an outline for my getting organized articles
     4. [X] Integrate blog posts into this outline
     5. [X] Write a script to convert .org files to .md files and copy
        them to the book directory
     6. [ ] Write the book. Chapter by Chapter goes below.
     7. [ ] Publish the ebook
     8. [ ] Upload the ebook to archive.org
     9. [ ] Update the download link on the landing page.
     10. [ ] Write a blog post announcing the book.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have checked off have of the items, but it is the easy stuff I've
checked off. So far I only have listed one items for writing the book
though I plan on adding check boxes underneath this item so I can
check off each chapter. The final check box is to review the entire
book and make any necessary corrections.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"STARTED" is a to-do state that I developed for my projects. More on
that when I discuss "TODO" in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org0fe9fe6" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org0fe9fe6"&gt;Setting Things Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org0fe9fe6"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up the git repository was very straight forward on &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.
Then I looked over my blog and copied the posts that applied into
that directory and updated the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I then wrote a landing page for the book. The idea of a landing page
is to have the potential reader focus on your book and the &lt;b&gt;Call to
Action&lt;/b&gt; which is for you, the reader, to click on the "buy" button.
My page is quite simple and does not have a "Download" button yet
since the book is not finished. You can look at it &lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/living-my-life-in-plain-text-page.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3d00dd0" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3d00dd0"&gt;Outlining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3d00dd0"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I then set about putting together an outline to help me think about
what the book should cover. This is not set in stone. More chapters
may appear and the ones listed here may disappear. This is what it
currently looks like in Org markup.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** Table of Contents
** Introduction -- what this book hopes to accomplish
** Thinking About Doing
** A Few Quick Notes on Orgmode Markup
** Setting up your Initial Emacs Configuration for Org
** Setting up a Calendar
** Seeing Your Calendar as an Agenda
** Making a To-do List
** How Deep Should You Go?
*** To-do Checkboxes
*** To-do Keywords
*** Priorities
** Revisiting the Agenda
*** Helpful keys in the Agenda -- archiving, saving, changing status
*** Seeing the Agenda on STartup
*** Remember to Refresh
** Capturing Information
*** Deciding what to Capture
** To Refile or Not to Refile
** Writing in Orgmode
** Exporting and Publishing in Orgmode
** Keeping Track of Expenses
** References
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org7542d41" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org7542d41"&gt;Promotion and Demotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org7542d41"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In looking this over, the first thing I want to do is change the
headline level. I need to move everything up one level so that heading
3s become heading2s and heading2s become heading1s
What I want to do is called promotion. I highlighted the text, went to
the org menu and found "promote" under the "edit structure" menu item.
There is a shortcut key you can use if you do this often enough to
remember it "m-s-left". You can also demote items "m-s-right"..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org9330537" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org9330537"&gt;Changing Headlines into Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org9330537"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can change headlines into lists and lists into headlines. I
changed my outline headings into an unordered list of to-do items by
highlighting them and then applying the command "c-c -". That's "c-c
hyphen". The "-" (hyphen) gives you the clue. The asterisks "*" are
replaced wit a hyphen "-". You can go the other way by using "c-c *" (asterisk).  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orge7e03ea" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orge7e03ea"&gt;Making an Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orge7e03ea"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orge78c6d3" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orge78c6d3"&gt;What Didn't Work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orge78c6d3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then I investigated how to make an epub. Pandoc can do this. One of
the examples I found showed how to put a bunch of markdown files in a
directory and then turn them into an ebook. Great, I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I tried to use org-publish to do this but I could not get a batch
transformation of all org files. I've tried this in the past and the
markdown export function still hangs. I think I had 30 buffers open wantiiting
for something. I have no idea what   
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I found this script on the &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org/faqs.html"&gt;pandoc site&lt;/a&gt; and modified it for my purpose:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
#!/bin/bash
# Convert all org files in a directory to markdown
# This script is to convert and move markdown into the book folder

for f in *.org;
do pandoc "$f" -s -o "${f%.org}.md";
done
mv *.md book/
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then I discovered I would have to include every filename in the
directory in my pandoc command. That seemed more trouble than it was
worth as the moment so I will just write in one file and perhaps split
it out at the end so that I can update it more easily. We'll see.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org66ebbf8" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org66ebbf8"&gt;What Did work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org66ebbf8"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had to add some YML stuff to the beginning of my file:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
---
title: Living My Life in Plain Text
author: Rill Woolnough
rights: Creative Commons Attribution Non-commercial ShareAlike
---
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's the pandoc command I am using:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
pandoc -o book.epub book.org --toc --toc-depth=3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org568499d" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org568499d"&gt;Reading the Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org568499d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So how to read it? Enter emacspeak. It uses the eww browser to render
the book. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
m-x     emacspeak-epub-open  ret
enter the path to the book ret
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Because Firefox is my default browser, the book opens there. There is
single letter navigation to move around in the book as if you are in a
regular web page. alt-f4 closes the book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3191d93" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3191d93"&gt;Back to Work!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3191d93"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now I'm going back to writing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Org</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 17:17:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>org-sort-list</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/09/org-sort-list/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
After sorting my lines using &lt;code&gt;m-x sort-lines&lt;/code&gt;, I have discovered org
itself has a sorting lines function. Here's how to use it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight the list you want to sort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;c-c ^&lt;/code&gt; (carat or s=6).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You will be prompted to indicate what kind of a sort you want.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a for alphabetical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f for function which I will not cover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;n for numeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x for checkboxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If these letters are capitalized, reverse order is used.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That's it. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/09/org-sort-list/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:15:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I Miss Her</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/06/i-miss-her/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I must have written this in the fall of 2006. Caitlin, my first
Seeing Eye dog, died on July 10, 2006. Elwood did not come into my
life until November 27th. I always remember Caitlin, my chocolate
Lab, on her birthday, September 6, 1992. Thinking about her still
brings tears to my eyes and a lump in my throat.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org8f020af" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org8f020af"&gt;I miss her&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org8f020af"&gt;
&lt;p class="verse"&gt;
In the daily tasks,&lt;br&gt;
in the ordinary doing of things,&lt;br&gt;
I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
25minutes to an appointment–&lt;br&gt;
I will take her out. There is time for that.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
I will sit  in my chair. She will come to be petted, to ask for a biscuit.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
I lay down in bed at night and listen for her breathing by the foot of the bed.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
I awake in the morning and check the time. I will dress and take her out.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
Her water bowl is no longer on the floor under the dishwasher door when I load and unload.&lt;br&gt;
And then, I miss her.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/06/i-miss-her/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 18:44:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Turning Off Auto-fill-mode in a Single Buffer</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/04/turning-off-auto-fill-mode-in-a-single-buffer/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
In my article on
&lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/02/using-checkboxes/"&gt;Using Checkboxes&lt;/a&gt; I discussed sorting lines in my ideas file. I went ahead
and added more ideas to the file. Because I sometimes forget details,
I decided to include many details in several entries.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Details are good, right? Well, not if they wrap to another line. This
messes up sorting since the sort doesn't know how to keep the
additional lines with their starting line. I knew that, but hoped
(unreasonably) that everything would stay together. Of course, it
didn't. So I had to look for a solution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The problem is simple enough. Auto-fill-mode is turned on by default.
In general, auto-fill-mode is a good thing. When the line gets too
long, Emacs inserts a line break and a new line is started. Happily,
when typing in org-mode as I was, Org appropriately wraps the line with a
two space indentation. Org knows my additional words belong to this
list item. HTML will know it, too, because Org will tell it by
enclosing the whole thing in "&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;" tags. But sort-lines is
emphatic that a line is a line.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The solution, not surprisingly, is to turn off auto-fill-mode in this
buffer. But how? I started searching for the answer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The readily available answer was this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
m-x auto-fill-mode
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This toggles auto-fill-mode on and off. If it is on to begin with, all
I have to do is toggle it off when I open the file and life is good.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Except … well, except that I want to write ideas with long
explanations because I forget. And it is &lt;b&gt;very&lt;/b&gt; likely I will forget
to do this.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Allthough it took some time, I finally found a way to do this so
auto-fill-mode would be turned off for the buffer and I don't have to
remember what to do.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I placed the following line at the top of my ideas file:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
;; -*- mode: org; mode: auto-fill -1; -*-
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I refresh the current buffer via the Org menu and autofilling stopped.
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: I did find I had to use "-1" rather than "0" to turn off
auto-fill.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Edited 2019-09-07. I originally had the mode as text when it should be org. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/04/turning-off-auto-fill-mode-in-a-single-buffer/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 18:56:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Walk in the Park with Nick</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/03/a-walk-in-the-park-with-nick/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Nick and I walked to catch a direct bus home from my salon
appointment. It was a nice day and catching the bus near the salon
would have required several complicated street crossings and a bus transfer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I had trouble connecting with my GPS. In the end, I think I hadn't
turned on my remote for my hearing aids. As a result, I was not fully
engaged with exactly where we were. Nick was so excited to go down new
streets. He became impatient with all my stopping and fiddling with technology.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Turning Nick around is always challenging. He seems to think that this
will make the walk end too soon even when we have walked for some
time./~/org/using-fly
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Finally we got onto a street that ran alongside the park. I was happy
because it meant we only had one big street crossing to go before the
bus stop.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Nick took the opportunity to turn into the park. We had walked through
there once before, but I did not have a good grasp on the macadam
paths. I thought I had turned Nick around to go back onto the
sidewalk, but he had other ideas.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I found myself going up hill and down at a great rate of speed. Happy
dog. GPS is basically useless in a park. At one point we came near to
some identifiable streets, but they were on the east side of the park.
I needed to be on the west side of the park.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We walked some more. I didn't think we were in any danger, but I did
wonder if Nick would ever consent to leave the park. I started
thinking about who I could call to come and find us. I had no good
options. I finally decided Nick would eventually get hungry and tired.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At last we exited the park. Unfortunately, Nick was going in the
opposite direction that I wanted to go. He was opposed to changing
direction. Eventually I prevailed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We walked alongside the park. We had often done this when we lived in
the high rise. Nick thinks of this route as a going home route so he
was less than enthusiastic.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When we got to the bus stop, Nick began to whine. The only thing worse
than walking home is not walking at all.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I will be curious to know how we do the next time we walk home from
the salon. Will a detour into the park be de rigueur.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Dog</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/03/a-walk-in-the-park-with-nick/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:33:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Checkboxes</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/02/using-checkboxes/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I wrote about
&lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/28/recurring-tasks-in-orgmode/"&gt;Recurring Tasks in Orgmode&lt;/a&gt; previously. Once I had this to-do working properly,
I went onto the next task. I wanted to list my ideas for articles and
bigger writing projects. In my opinion, I did not need to set this all
up as a big list of to-dos. That certainly becomes overwhelming to
me.I might just stop writing altogether because the ideas keep coming
but the time and patience to write them may not be available at the
moment. I do
want to be sure I have a stash of ideas to choose from when I am able
to sit down and write out a complete article.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I created a file name "ideas.org". I inserted three headings:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
* Writing Ideas Big and Small
** Blog Ideas [/]
** Bigger WRiting Projects [/]

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You may have noticed that at the end of the second level headings
there are two square brackets "[]" enclosing a slash "/". More on this
later.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgacf951f" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgacf951f"&gt;Organizing the list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgacf951f"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At first I thought I would just write a list like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- smart quotess and other typography
- less than shortcuts in orgmode
- Braile pack at public museum
- photo op with Nick
- a walk in the park with Nick
- using org capture
- Using checkboxes in org

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then I thought about using checkboxes so I could check them off as I
went. Now this section of the file looks like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- [ ] smart quotess and other typography
- [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
- [ ] Braile pack at public museum
- [ ] photo op with Nick
- [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
- [ ] using org capture
- [ ] Using checkboxes in org

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Who knows, you might even see some of these articles in the future!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org525edff" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org525edff"&gt;Why Use Checkboxes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org525edff"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Why use checkboxes? After all, I could simply delete the item from the
file once I published it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It's a good point. I decided to try this methodology just to see how I
liked it and for two other reasons:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would let me know how I was doing at keeping up with my ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would let me know if I needed to be thinking more about writing
opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It seems to me that a writer is stuck here: Coming up with ideas and
getting them written.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org6e721c1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org6e721c1"&gt;Using the Checkboxes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org6e721c1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To check off an item, press "c-c c-c" on that line. Then you have:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
:- [X] Using checkboxes in org
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's what the heading now looks like:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** Blog Ideas [1/7]

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If I turn the "/" (slash) into a percent sign (%) it looks like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
:** Blog Ideas &lt;code&gt;[14%]&lt;/code&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If I feel ambitious, I can delete these lines or I can sort them so
that all the unchecked boxes are together.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgc1a4de7" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgc1a4de7"&gt;Sorting Lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgc1a4de7"&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Type "m-x sort-lines". All the checked off items will be gathered
together at the end of the list. The items appear in alphabetical
order.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- [ ] Braile pack at public museum
- [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
- [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
- [ ] photo op with Nick
- [ ] smart quotess and other typography
   - [ ] using org capture
- [X] Using checkboxes in org 

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This list now is in a different order than the way I originally
wrote it down. I can read through it until I come to an item with a
checkbox. I know there are no more new items.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If I want to sort in reverse order, I type: "c-u m-x sort-lines".
Here is what I now have:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- [X] Using checkboxes in org
- [ ] using org capture
- [ ] smart quotess and other typography
- [ ] photo op with Nick
- [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
- [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
- [ ] Braile pack at public museum

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I don't think I will use this ordering unless I need a confidence
boost. I would have to go past everything I've already done.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Org</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/02/using-checkboxes/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 15:32:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Recurring Tasks in Orgmode</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/28/recurring-tasks-in-orgmode/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Edited on 2019/09/01 to correct an error with tasks that needed to be
re-scheduled differently in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfe046a7" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgfe046a7"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgfe046a7"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I have been keeping a list of to-dos in a file called "organizer.org".
(I'm not sure if it actually keeps me organized, but I like the idea
of having a list of tasks, especially tasks I might forget about.) At
the top level I have three headlines:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasks. These are the one off sorts of tasks that it would be
labor-intensive to categorize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website. This is where I put items related to maintaining my
website (where you are most likely reading this article) and ideas
for writing new articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing. Separate from writing for my website, I list longer pieces
here both fiction and non-fiction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My "init.el" file for Emacs has a line in it to display my weekly
agenda view.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
(setq initial-buffer-choice 'org-agenda-list)
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This agenda view shows my diary for the week as well as any tasks with
either a scheduled start date or end date, i.e., deadline.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org2150c22" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org2150c22"&gt;Writing a Good To-do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org2150c22"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A basic rule of thumb is to write a to-do that you can actually get
done. It has to be specific enough so that you know when you've
started it and when you can check it off your list, that is, mark it
done. I had this to-do which is more an aspiration than a to-do.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** TODO Publish at least one blog post weekly to keep website fresh

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The intent is clear enough: one blog post to be completed every
week.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My mother kept a calendar on the kitchen wall. She was fussy about it.
She wanted big blank blocks in which to write. She wrote everything
down. She had codes for each of us. She often would say the item and
the person's initials as she wrote.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In my mother's calendar world, the blog post could be written in and
even X'ed out when done and then been re-written on the next line of
blocks for the month. She may have even just drawn a straight line
through every Tuesday.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have several good to-dos already in my organizer file:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** TODO Pay rent
   DEADLINE: &amp;lt;2019-09-01 Sun +1m&amp;gt;
** TODO Give Nick his heart worm pill
   DEADLINE: &amp;lt;2019-09-13 Fri +1m&amp;gt;

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
These tasks can be marked as done. Org will advance the date
by one month and they will again appear in my weekly agenda view. The
day of the week will change, but not the day of the month.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org4044145" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org4044145"&gt;An Interim Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org4044145"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I started marking my website refresh to-do as done when I wrote and
posted a new article. After marking it done and recording the name of
the article in the comments, I marked the to-do as "TODO" to start the
process all over again. This seems quite unappealing to me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org6ee2973" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org6ee2973"&gt;A Better Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org6ee2973"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In reading through
&lt;a href="https://orgmode.org/manual/Repeated-tasks.html"&gt;Repeated Tasks&lt;/a&gt; I realized that my article writing to-do is not like
paying rent or giving Nick his pill. If I do not write a blog article
on a given week, I don't need to catch up. I can pick up at any time
and start posting on a regular basis. It is clear looking through my
archives and at other people's blogs this is what happens all the
time. I am writing these articles because I want to write them. I
don't need to write them. I enjoy posting and then marking my success
by calling this to-do done. In the days of paper and pen, people
enjoyed drawing a line through an item on a list. (Never using this
medium, I was always jealous of their satisfaction. People wrote
noisily and with a flourish.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I now find out Org has a solution for my task.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org1251945" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org1251945"&gt;My New To-do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org1251945"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here is what I came up with for my article writing to-do.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** TODO Publish at least one blog post weekly to keep website fresh
   DEADLINE: &amp;lt;2019-08-27 Tue .+3d&amp;gt;

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This suggests I have a 3 day deadline for writing a weekly article.
No, I haven't lost my mind. If I am writing regularly, I will write
more than one blog post a week and I want to honor that, but my
general goal is to be sure I write at least one post every week.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When I mark this task as done, three days will be added to the deadline. If the
deadline is in the past, another three days will be added until the deadline
is in the future. In this way, the three-day deadline may also move
throughout the week. For example, if I complete this task today,
Tuesday, it will have a deadline of Friday. If I don't complete
it until Monday, it will then have a deadline of the following
Thursday, almost two weeks after its original deadline.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you want this task to always be due on a Tuesday,for example,  use
"&lt;del&gt;+"(plus plus) instead
of ".&lt;/del&gt;" (dot plus.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/28/recurring-tasks-in-orgmode/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 19:11:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Org Tables with Emacspeak</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/27/using-org-tables-with-emacspeak/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Write your post here.** Introduction
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I wanted to know how much my subscriptions were costing me every
month. Subscription fatigue is a popular topic on tech talk shows so I
wanted to see how my useage stacked up and if there was anything
outrageous I could cut.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are a number of tools at my disposal:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Perkins Brailler and a sheet of paper. I still know how to add up
a column of figures manually.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A spreadsheet program. Let me count the options I have, not going
into how well I think they work or how well I know them.
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Excel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibriOffice Calc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dismal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Although not in my little list above, I know word processor programs
have tables and the possibility of formulas, but I decided I could
investigate org tables. I could report on their accessibility with help from Emacspeak.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgdee892e" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgdee892e"&gt;Setting Up A Table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgdee892e"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I decided to create a table with two columns, "ITEM" for the name of
the subscription and "ExPENSE" for the monthly amount I am
spending.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There's nothing fancy about setting up an org table. The vertical bar
character "|" delimits columns. If a "|" is the first character in a
line, org understands this to be a table. A two column table with one
row looks like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;

| | |

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But I need a table with two headers, a horizontal rule between my
headings and my subscriptions and one row to start.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: You need a header row with a horizontal rule underneath it   if you want to total a column of numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Type the line
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="example"&gt;

|ITEM|ExPENSE|

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Press return. Don't worry about white space
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Type "|-" (vertical bar followed immediately by a hyphen) and press
tab.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
| ITEM | ExPENSE |
|------+---------|
|      |         |
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Now you have a table ready for input.Your column headings have
white space around them and your horizontal rule is filled in. The
vertical bars to define the columns in the new row are in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orged08adb" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orged08adb"&gt;Entering Data into A Table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orged08adb"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once the table is set up like this, it is an easy process to fill in many lines of data.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With point at the third position, type "Amazon Prime".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press tab. Point is at the third position after the second "|".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type "8.25" for one month of the $99 subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here's what the table now looks like. Notice that the columns have
been adjusted to accommodate the longer text of "Amazon Prime".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
| ITEM         | EXPENSE  |
|--------------+---------|
| Amazon Prime |       8.25   |
|              |              |
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It is important to realize that point is now in the second column.
Either use s=tab to move back one field to the first column or c-a to
go to the beginning of the line and c-f to move to the right of the "|".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgadea855" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgadea855"&gt;Summing Up Expenses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgadea855"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When I thought I had listed all my subscriptions, I made another
horizontal rule.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I typed the word "Total" in the first column.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pressed tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pressed "C-c +" (c-c then the plus sign). This summed up my
expenses and put it in the echo line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pressed "c-y" to paste (yank) it into the table at point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now I could read the number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is fine, but if I added another subscription (perish the
thought!) I would have to go through the process of updating the total
more or less manually. I needed a formula that I could rerun at any
time. Who knows. I might even drop a subscription down the road.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfa71b7b" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgfa71b7b"&gt;Some Discoveries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgfa71b7b"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I created a much more complicated table with many headings for
different kinds of expenses. Most of every column had white space in
it with a few numbers. This doesn't work in Org. The columns cannot be
summarized. Following the example of&lt;a href="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/spreadsheet.html"&gt;Lots of Small Spreadsheets&lt;/a&gt; I broke
my mammoth spreadsheet into six little ones:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subscriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rent and such&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;health and wellness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;food and drink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dog (for my Seeing Eye dog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then I created a seventh table to summarize them all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org8255836" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org8255836"&gt;Naming Tables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org8255836"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If each of these tables has a unique name, any field in that table can be
referenced elsewhere in the Org universe. It looks like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
#+NAME: subscriptions
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Put this name at the top of the table above the header row. Don't have
any white space in-between this line and the header line. Org needs to
understand they are connected.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org98d079b" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org98d079b"&gt;How Org References Rows and Columns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org98d079b"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To find out where you are in a table, use "c-c ?" (c-c question mark).
To hear the reference again, press "c-e a". You can do this as many
times as you need to until you have it in your mind. I don't know of a
way to put it on the clipboard to be yanked into a text file to be
interrogated.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The readout is in the form line number which is prefixed by the "@" (at sign) followed by the
word "col" followed by the column designation in the form "$" (dollar
sign) followed by the column position followed by the compound
expression of row plus column. Finally, a more conventional
spreadsheet reference. So the field in the seventh row in the fifth column is "@7$5" or "G5".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org5c6e3ee" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org5c6e3ee"&gt;Putting It Altogether&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org5c6e3ee"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Each of our little tables needs a formula to sum up the expenses
listed in column 2. You write this formula this way:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
#+TBLFM: @&amp;gt;$2=vsum(@2..@-1)
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"#+TBLFM:" follows the table itself with no white space. I could
not get more than one of these to work per table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The left hand side of the equation shows where to put the answer.
Put it in the last row, second column.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"vsum" is an Emacs calc function. It will summarize the column for us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within the parentheses is the range: from the second row to the
next to last row in the second column. Org does not count the
horizontal lines but it will stop any calculation when it
encounters one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press "c-c c-c" on this line and voila! The total appears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Always blank out your field(s) before initiating a
calculation. You will get some strange numbers if you don't.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3933ab6" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3933ab6"&gt;The Final Summation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3933ab6"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, I needed to add the totals from the six tables into
the seventh one. Obviously, I could look at each number and copy it over,
but what fun is that? Besides, every time I added an item to one of
the tables, I would have to copy a new number into the correct field.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Enter "#+NAME:" to save the day.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I wrote a formula to pick up the total amount from each table, copy it
to the appropriate line in the second column of my summary table and
add it all up. No matter how hard I tried, I couldn't get the hang of
doing these remote references within the table so I have one huge
"#+TBLFM:" line. It may not be pretty but it works! Here's what it
looks like. It will probably wrap on your screen, but trust me, it's
one line in my file.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
#+TBLFM:@2$2=remote(subscriptions,@&amp;gt;$2)::@3$2=remote(rent-and-such,@&amp;gt;$2)::@4$2=remote(health-and-wellness,@&amp;gt;$2)::@5$2=remote(dog,@&amp;gt;$2)::@6$2=remote(food-and-drink,@&amp;gt;$2)::@7$2=remote(misc,@&amp;gt;$2)::@&amp;gt;$2=vsum(@2$2..@&amp;gt;-1$2)
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The double "::" (colon) concatenates each equation to the next. When it
all finally worked, the entire column was filled in and the grand
total appeared. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org588fc64" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org588fc64"&gt;Some Observations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org588fc64"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"C-c spc" is a great keybinding to know. It blanks out a field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning how to delete a column or row is useful. Don't be too
zealous. You'll end up wiping out all your hard work entering it.
Moving rows up and down can be accomplished with keybindings, too.
You can learn about all these by going through the tbl menu option. It's good when you don't remember a keybinding like I do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did not find the formula debugger very helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had trouble when my table only had one line of data. The range
confused the program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need to, you can export your table to a csv file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being very specific in formulas helps a lot. There are some
shortcuts for cell descriptions, but some of them were harder to
understand and use for me. When I got specific, my formulas worked
much better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emacspeak keybindings appear to be duplicates of the org ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With simple tables, it is not too hard to review the table with speech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org8334c17" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org8334c17"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org8334c17"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I really like using org for this work. My file is a text file and
easily understood and modified as needed. With a little editing of the
names, I can have a file with each month under a separate headline. I
could keep year-to-date figures as well as compare expenses on a
yearly basis. There is the potential to have a unique identifier for each field.
Tracking utility bills, for example, year over year could come in very handy. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/27/using-org-tables-with-emacspeak/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 19:10:17 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>