<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about Biblical Reflection)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/biblical-reflection.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 16:52:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>January 2</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/02/january-2/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I am reading the Psalms and thinking about goals, Psalm 34
presents three. I will look at them individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will bless the LORD at all times; &lt;br&gt;
his praise shall ever be in my mouth.&lt;br&gt;
Psalm 34:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a strong suit of mine. It is one form of prayer that does
not come naturally to me. 
Blessing and praise are not always my default. I am trying to say
"Have a blessed day" when I leave my bus, but "Thank you" comes far
more naturally. I have tried writing in a gratitude journal, but both
journaling and finding ways to be grateful in a meaningful way is
hard. I could write almost every Wednesday and Thursday: "I am
grateful for my Bible study." and it would cease to be gratitude. It
would be a item to tick off. This would not mean I wasn't grateful. It
would just mean that the gratitude itself would stop being one and
just be what I wrote down for those days. I could probably find a
weekly gratitude for each day and then the exercise would collapse
under its own weight. It is like going around the Thanksgiving table
and people say the same thing every year, a version of "For health and
strength and daily food we praise thy name, O Lord." I want my
blessing and praise to be in the moment. Often my moments are focused
elsewhere, like not falling when I am stepping off the bus or not
losing my sense of direction when walking home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come, children, and listen to me;&lt;br&gt;
I will teach you the fear of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Psalm 34:11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't do this much when I am participating in Bible study or
preaching, but I think it is a worthwhile goal. Thinking of Jesus as
ever present, God with us. Some may argue that Jesus came so that we
might not be afraid of God, of judgment, that Jesus brought us grace,
but we had that already in the Hebrew scriptures. God is slow to anger
and abounding in steadfast love. I think of fear of the Lord as
reverence and acknowledgment of God's presence so I want that
awareness to be closer to me than it currently is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My third selection is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turn from evil and do good;&lt;br&gt;
seek peace and pursue it.&lt;br&gt;
Psalm 34:14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lofty one in the starkness of biblical absolutes. This is
more of a consciousness thing, being aware of when I fail to do good
and when I need to actively seek a more peaceful interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose all three really boil down to this: "I will bless the Lord
at all times."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Biblical Reflection</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/02/january-2/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 16:06:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>January 1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/01/january-1-2020/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read this webpage today. &lt;a href="http://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/Christmas/HolyName_RCL.html"&gt;Holy Name&lt;/a&gt; Without a doubt, the hearer of these texts are to concentrate on the name of Jesus and of all the ways we might engage God's name. But being a more perverse person, that is not where my mind went. In Philippians,Paul says "Let the same mind be in you that was in Christ Jesus." (2:5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? I have read these words many times and have often wondered but never stopped to think about them separately. Yes. Yes. Every knee should bow and all that, but what would it mean to have the same mind as Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is Jesus' servanthood, Jesus' willingness to do God's will, to be God with us rather than God apart from us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I begin the year thinking I might have a goal this year to come back to these readings and be Christ to those I meet. It's been a Christian practice forever, but I forget it all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People get nervous around other people when they start spouting religion or say things like, "Jesus loves you." I am not that sort of person. But I can channel it and act as if I had said it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be mindful of having the mind of Jesus this year. Who knows. It might even become habitual. And isn't that the point of resolutions anyway?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Biblical Reflection</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2020/01/01/january-1-2020/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 22:59:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>