<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about Bible)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/bible.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 19:16:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Thinking About the Vine</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/15/thinking-about-the-vine/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I don't know that I am going to write a proper flash sermon on this,
but I can't help thinking about the vineyard in Isaiah 5 and Psalm 80.
They are the assigned texts for the Revised Common Lectionary for
Track 1 Year C.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have read these texts often since I usually review them for John 15
"I am the vine and you are the branches".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One of the things that continues to surprise me while reading the
parable in Isaiah 5 is the violence of God's actions:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking away its hedge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making it a wasteland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not providing any rain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In some translations, there is a distinction between grapes and bad
fruit. A better way to think of this  is cultivated grapes and wild
grapes.. Some translations maintain this distinction which is helpful.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The plantings, the vines, are identified as the people. Their crop is
not the tasty grapes but the wild grapes of oppression and injustice.
That is what is making God angry.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here God is saying that God created an environment for justice and
freedom. Instead, God finds an environment of injustice and, in some
translations, bloodshed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The parable begins with the writer saying that he or she is singing a
song to his/her beloved. The singer is on the side of justice and
righteousness along with God, but as prophet, he/she is pointing out
the state of the people as God sees them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
These chapters we have been reading as part of the lectionary really
point out God's frustration at the people who claim to worship God but
behave counter to God's intentions for humanity.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Bible</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/15/thinking-about-the-vine/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 15:36:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Psalm 64</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/psalm-64/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have been trying to read a psalm every day. My Old Testament
professor Dr. Robinson said it would change my life. He said that
twenty years ago (that's a scary thought in and of itself). I've never
succeeded at doing this, but it's never too late to give it a shot. I
would read all the psalms twice through in one year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I've been suggesting we read a psalm at the end of our Bible study on
Thursdays. I don't do it every week, but it turns out one of the
participants doesn't like the psalms. I realized that reading one
every week allows us to work through all 150 psalms over time (three
years or so) without getting bogged down in the book of psalms. That
would make things easier for the participant who doesn't like them.
Someone is marking them off as we go.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is a long introduction to reading Psalm 64. I started at Psalm 61
because that is the psalm we read last Thursday and it seemed to be a
good place to start. The problem of embarking on such a task is that
I've read Psalm 1 a lot and never gotten very far after that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I can't remember ever reading Psalm 64 before. No doubt I have, but
nothing stood out to mean. This morning, however, in the wake of the
terrible shootings at El Paso and Youngstown, I couldn't help thinking of
all those bullets or, as the psalmist put it, arrows. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
David is talking about words, not literal weapons, but it doesn't much matter in the
context of the psalm. Behind the bullets were evil words. And evil
words and hatred are at the crux of the problem in this country. It
there weren't so many evil words flying about like arrows, people
shopping on a Saturday morning for school supplies or going out for a
fun-filled evening wouldn't be dead–terrible! Unspeakable evil!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I take comfort in verse 8:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="verse"&gt;
Their own tongues shall ruin them.&lt;br&gt;
All who see them will shake their heads.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://worldenglishbible.org"&gt;World English Bible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Bible</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/psalm-64/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 20:07:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More Thoughts on Amos 7</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/12/more-thoughts-on-amos-7/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Jeroboam II had a 40-year reign. During that time, the country
prospered. Reading through the Book of Amos, it is clear that only
some were doing well. Granted, Amos was from Judah and the Lord
sent him. Setting aside the question of worshiping God outside of
Jerusalem and the synchronistic character of temple worship in Israel,
Amos inveighs against personal excess and unethical business
practices. Israel is rotten at its core, straying far from the
precepts God has prescribed for the people in their interpersonal
relationships and societal responsibilities for the poor and needy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It is astounding that twenty-five years after Jeroboam II's death,
Israel fell to the Assyrians. Assyria forcibly deported many to the
far reaches of its empire, effectively dispersing Israel's people so
that ethnic and religious identity of the people evaporated as they
were absorbed by other cultures and religions. Although the land
remained, Israel and its people were absolutely gone except in
the prophetic imagination.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What makes reading Amos so disturbing are the parallels to our own
country and culture. How close to annihilation are we? Could life as
we know it come tumbling down as quickly as it did for the people of
Israel?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Who will stand up and prophesy to the people and will anyone believe
God's prophet? Or are we doomed to repeat  the experience of ancient Israel?
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Bible</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/12/more-thoughts-on-amos-7/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 20:27:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding Good News in Amos and Psalm 82</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/11/finding-good-news-in-amos-and-psalm-82/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
These are the Hebrew Scripture readings for July 14, 2019 in the
United Methodist Church.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I am not preaching, but a friend asked me to find good news in Amos
7:1-17 (the whole chapter). Here's what is going on:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things are going well in Israel. The economy is humming
along. Business is good. There are no imminent threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Israel has set up a variant of worship within its borders, not
supporting, going to or wanting to worship in Jerusalem in the
kingdom of Judah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite the good economy and the absence of threats foreign or
domestic, the poor are suffering. Trickle down economics didn't work
then either and many of them are being cheated when they buy goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God sends Amos, whose name means &lt;i&gt;burden-bbearer&lt;/i&gt; to prophesy.
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amos is from Judah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amos is not a professional prophet. He has not attended prophet
school. (Yes, they had them back then.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amos seems himself as a shepherd and a sycamore tree farmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Common English Bible (2010) agrees with my Old Testament
professor who insisted that Amos speaks about himself in the
present tense. He still tends sheep and fruit trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The word is bad for Israel and particularly Amaniah in this chapter,
but the good news is directed to God's championing the poor. Things
are out of alignment in Israel. That is why God shows Amos the plumb
line. Measure Israel. See how askew it is. It needs to be brought back
to plumb, to act, as Micah puts it, like this: "… to do justly, to love mercy,
and to walk humbly with your God" Micah 6:8b NKJV).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Amos bears the burden of speaking God's word in a foreign country to
hostile audiences. He does it because he is obedient to God's call and
because the people of Israel are God's people, too.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Psalm 82 is subtitled, in my New King James Version of the Bible, &lt;i&gt;An
Appeal to Justice&lt;/i&gt;. When we cannot bring things into plumb, we ask God
to do it. We are confident that God will do it even if it is not on
our time table.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The psalmist says"All the foundations of the earth are unstable"
(Psalm 82:5c NKJV).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the Gospel for Sunday, Jesus shows how the good Samaritan behaves
towards the helpless man and
declares that he has fulfilled the law to love his neighbor as
himself. The Samaritan was able to do this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tend the injured man's wounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring him to the inn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage the innkeeper to continue to care for the injured man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promised to reimburse the innkeeper for any expense above what the
Samaritan had already paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes the fix is beyond our individual or collective ability. Then
we appeal to God for the justice we are unable to deliver.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is not an excuse. It is a reality.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Anaziah and Jeroboam were powerful men.  As such, God  charged them to
care for the poor and needy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
God's charge has not changed. Providing safe and sanitary conditions
for migrants at our southern border is not a political matter. God has
charged us to care for those who are in need and for the sojourner
among us. It is a question of carrying out the will of God–Thy will
be done.   
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Bible</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/11/finding-good-news-in-amos-and-psalm-82/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 16:28:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coffee and Nehemiah</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/01/10/coffee-and-nehemiah/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I sat down today with Paul and later Jason to discuss my texts for January 27th. I primarily wanted to talk to Paul about Nehemiah 8 and if my analysis of the text was consistent with his understanding of Nehemiah and its place in the history of Israel. Paul is a thoughtful student and teacher so I learned a great deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Jason joined us after his meeting, I explored the practicalities of preaching at St. Luke's. Jason's sermons are about 7 minutes long. I'm used to having more time to develop my sermon so cutting back to between 700 and 1000 words will be challenging. I am starting to think of this as my flash sermon as flash fiction stories are no longer than a thousand words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a basic summary of what we worked out today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over 7 days, the people (which includes women and children as well as men) here the Torah read aloud. There are break out groups where the Levites translate and instruct small groups of the people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would appear that Ezra reads more than a law code but reads a great deal of the Torah. If you postulate he read for 3 hours and a person reads 30 pages an hour and he read for 7 days, that works out to 630 pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A further postulation is that Ezra started with Genesis and read through the Torah so that the people heard the entire story of God's saving work including fetching the people bak from Egypt and entering the promised land.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people are in mourning but they are told to rejoice. This is a happy story because it is the account of God's faithfulness to the people, the story of his mighty acts to save.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nehemiah prays at the opening of the book that God continues to be faithful so that the people may not be scattered  again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;St. Paul speaks to the Corinthians about being the body of Christ, being one body. Each person is important in their own right. The Corinthians wanted to compete with one another to have the best gifts but Paul tells them that each person in the  congregation  is equally important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus widens the idea of the congregation to include the captive and the disabled. All are welcome and all have gifts to share.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a joyful task. The body grows. No one need be afraid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Witth 23% of Americans identifying as atheist or of no religion, there are lots of people to extend an invitation to. Our message is one of joy, that God's mighty acts continue and that our worship and community is joyful. We are not here to condemn and to mourn our shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are sent out with gladness and singleness of heart to share this joy with everyone we meet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Bible</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/01/10/coffee-and-nehemiah/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 01:42:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>