<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about Captain Star Runner)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/captain-star-runner.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 19:16:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Magic is Difficult</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/01/07/magic-is-difficult/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have really struggled with writing my next Ronnie Camberwell mystery. I was so pleased with myself about exploring magic, but magic has proved to be difficult. Magic has a cost and although I have figured out what the cost is to Ronnie as a result of her careless attitude toward magic, I cannot figure out the cost of magic to the wizard on an ongoing basis. The wizards are just gifted with the ability to perform magic and beyond that, I don't know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've explored the political consequences and that doesn't seem to hold water. Exile would break a society apart. Inherited magic doesn't make sense either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I don't have a good reason for wizards to have the ability to do magic to hang out together in the Magic Lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my mind, the Magic Lands feel very medieval. Perhaps this is just a trope. On the other hand, I have always felt there is something cinister about the place, as if it itself is held fast by a very powerful spell. Who does the work around here? Are they slaves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is just no energy or enthusiasm to write this story.  I might have to recast it and I started to do this by introducing Captain Star Runner into the plot line. I want to develop something which involves these two characters to write regularly this winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Captain Star Runner</category><category>Ronnie Camberwell</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/01/07/magic-is-difficult/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 06:08:02 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>