<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about guide dogs)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/guide-dogs.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 01:10:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Preparing for a New Dog</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2016/07/24/preparing-for-a-new-dog/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been putting off writing this article. for some time because preparing for a new dog is more than looking forward to a long-anticipated outing. Getting a new guide dog requires physical, mental and emotional preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="thephysical"&gt;The Physical&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a guide dog ages, it slows down, just like we do. Because their life span is shorter, the slow down is more noticeable. Consequently, I have been walking slower and slower for some time. Now that I am using a white cane, I am walking even more slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remedy this, I worked out on a treadmill twice a week. This is not intensive training, I know, but I hope it will get my body used to moving faster and I will be more ready to walk with a much younger dog in his or her prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep up with my Senior Center exercise class twice a week. I also go to yoga classes two evenings a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treadmill work will not continue when I return home. It is too hard on my legs and feet and does not fill in for walking. The walking pace is quite artificial and does not represent the way I walk with my dog. The exercise and yoga classes will. continue. I am switching to three yoga classes and one exercise class. My plan is to add several long walks each week. We will have to learn new routes together to accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have changed my exercise program for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The yoga classes are more intense for me. I think I am ready for this increase in activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The yoga classes are all in the same venue—a clean space where the dog will be in the same general place under the same conditions for each class. I am hopeful this will allow us to develop good habits which will last for our entire partnership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id="mentalandemotionalpreparation"&gt;Mental and Emotional Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have lumped these two categories together although I know they can be quite different. I am not sure where one ends and the other begins for me in my preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="startingtheprocess"&gt;Starting the Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of preparing for a new dog begins with the old dog. For a year or more I talked about getting a new dog. I was trying to talk myself into it. I made excuses: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The floor was too hard for old bones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With time, the dogs just get too smart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I told myself my dog, Elwood, was still doing his job well–and he did up to the last.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this made it very difficult to sit down at the computer in January and start filling out the “paperwork”. The link “When partnerships end” on the website didn’t help. I wanted my partnership with Elwood to last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="waiting"&gt;Waiting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elwood and I kept working together while I waited. I had a tentative class date. It passed. The time was upon me to say good-bye to Elwood and send him off with his new family on their all-summer vacation. I hope to and a half months away will solidify his affection for his new family–people he has known for two/thirds of his life–and be enough of a separation from me that seeing me again will not divide his loyalty. (Elwood is a very loyal dog.) He is also very, very clear about who puts food in his bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiting for a class date to be confirmed is a very discouraging process. It is easy to place blame on others or to be convinced there is favoritism. I have no idea what has taken so long. I just can’t imagine the “right dog” is that hard to find or I am such a unique individual that the right dog is so hard to come by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="gettingreadytotravel"&gt;Getting Ready to Travel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the line, I stopped liking travel. Perhaps it was the number of moves I have made. I just want to stay where I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I have realized I am limiting my travel so much that I am not doing the things I want to do. To this end, I have set myself some goals and I have already achieved one of them by using Uber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a white cane, I learned my neighborhood in a different way. I hope it will help me become more independent and confident when I return with my new dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although saying good-bye to a partner is excruciatingly painful, I am confident I have done as much preparation as I could to be able to start the adventure of a new and successful partnership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>guide dogs</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2016/07/24/preparing-for-a-new-dog/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 07:07:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Library Journey</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/21/library-journey/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elwood and I were finally able to run an errand outside by ourselves. In fact, I got sweaty on the way home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to return some books to the library. the library has a wonderful system whereby I could opt in to receive email notices when books are due. In fact, i had three to return so off we went this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of dry pavement out there but also a lot of slush and some uncleared places. There is still a high snowbank with a narrow opening at one intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned something new about the Trekker Breeze GPS. I used my route to get to the library. I really don't need it anymore. Street announcements are sufficient. Instead of backtracking, I tried selecting the landmark of my home from the library to generate a route. As the library is in a strip mall, the Breeze informed me that I was too far from any road to generate a route. Elwood and I made our way to South Park Street and I tried again. I was successful. Elwood sat down to wait for me to be ready. These people and their toys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was curious to know how I would be sent. The Breeze retraced the route I had taken. It's probably the shortest way. However, I discovered another limitation. When we got to the West Wingra intersection, it told me to turn left but did not indicate if I should cross West Wingra or not. If I did not, I would be on the bike path. It might be difficult to discern where to cross Wingra to take advantage of the crosswalk. There is not a light at this 3-way intersection. Making the crossing with the light at the 4-way intersection at park allows me to simply turn when I get to South. I suppose this is knowing your area and trial and error to pick the correct strategy. The GPS does not ever tell you which side of the street you are on.  Apparently all calculations are from the middle of the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elwood did very well today, including stopping because a vehicle was in a driveway waiting to pull out. I could not hear the vehicle with my hood up and it idling nor could I see it with the angle of the sun. He does this so well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blindness</category><category>guide dogs</category><category>technology</category><category>trekker breeze</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/21/library-journey/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 17:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On Bones and Things</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/17/on-bones-and-things/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elwood arrived on my lap to say it was almost 8 o'clock. Time to go out. So we did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been snowing. Not much you understand. I was wearing my crocs, of course, klogs, lined but still the holes on top can take in snow and there's not a whole lot of insolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Elwood did his thing and then decided to sniff. New snow. Much snuffling sounds. Where is the stoop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to be fair, Elwood probably did show it to me and I wandered away, but it was not clear because of the new snow. We started moving up and down the driveway, me in my crocs and Elwood happily snuffling away with much volume and enthusiasm. I finally found that I was in the right place thru Elwood's half-hearted direction and the light over the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I need to say that as we were going out into the hallway, Elwood was very insistant that we go out while he held a bone in his mouth. The bone ended up in the hallway outside the apartment as we dashed to the outside door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon our return inside, I directed Elwood to find his bone. He dashed away, jerking the leash out of my hand and gobbled up his bone. We went inside. I took the leash off. Where is the bone? Bone? I can't find it! I opened the door. Where's your bone. Here it is. Back inside, please. Both Elwood and bone are now safely inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of energy and so do others keep track of Elwood's bones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date:
today at 8:21 PM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>guide dogs</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/17/on-bones-and-things/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 02:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>