<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about mobile)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/mobile.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 01:10:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>11/4/08</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/11/04/11408-2/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such a beautiful day ! Elwood and I walked up to Curve. The woman I had met when the mobility instructor and I first checked it out was there. "You came back," she said. I explained I had come last Thursday. It turns out she is off Wednesday and Thursday. I had an omelet--definitely dinner, huge and good.It was twice as much as the eggs I had last week so they're a better bet most of the time. Then we walked back, definitely our exercise for the day. The people who sit at the counter help out with seating. We sat against the wall because I thought it might protect Elwood better. It's tight for a left-anded eater.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In other food news, my friend baked a wonderful loaf in my bread machine. I now have bread machine and bbread in the house. She also gave me the recipe and the ingredients should be arriving with my other groceries later today. The coop has dried mulberries so I will find out what they taste like. I only know what Dr. Souix's POV character saw on Mulberry Street and to think there is a Mulbery Street in Trenton. I also learned, because the coop gives such info, that most dried fruit has sweetener of some kind added as well as oil. Prices are all over the place, but fortunately I can purchase small amounts. I also learned about salt since I needed some of that, too, for the bread. Sea salt comes fine and coarse and in bulk. So does the laundry detergent. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I stopped at the local grocery store yesterday. Unfortunately, they gave me vanilla yogurt instead of plain. This particular vanilla wasn't horrifically sweet. It tasted almost like vanilla pudding. I understand it is difficult because they look alike. I will have to ask for someone who reads English well. The woman that most often helps is a good egg, but I do not think she reads well in English and depends on what things look like and the peopole in the particular departments for assistance.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/11/04/11408-2/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 18:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>11/4/08</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/11/04/11408/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went to vote this morning. I was 553 around 9:45. My polling place is in a low income apartment building. So there are the people sitting outside. It is teashirt weather in Madison. Snow and rain possible for the weekend, but right now we are having weather in the 60s and 70s. Then there's inside. The lobby has people in it, too, all over anxious to be helpful. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On Sunday one of my ride companions showed me the inside of the building. She lives there. The elevator was out of order and we did the stairs because the voting is set up in the community room. Today the elevator was working. It's brailled but of course I had to figure out where I was going. I decided 1. There were people outside of the room. It turns out the poll people do not officially recognize whoever these people were as being allowed to be within range of a polling place. Nevertheless, they were helpful in directing me. A man then took me to the first table and yes, indeed, I am registered. He thought I needed to register. I brought my utility bills just in case. I did check on the Wisconsin web site and saw my voter registration information and a sample ballot. I then went to another table, got my ballot and then went to a place to mark it. No curtained area.  Just a place to stand. The man marked my ballot for me. Then we went and put it into the optacle scanner. That was a little tricky, getting it straight. A corner got bent but I've fed enough dollars into vending machines to smooth that out. Then the form grabbed, like the shreadder,and the computer sound indicated it was tabulated. Back to the elevator and figuring out that I had to push 2 to get back to the lobby. Then all the people and finally outside.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;No waiting yet obviously a lot of people have already come through. Wisconsin has beentelling people to vote between 9 and 4:30 if possible. No stickers. No fuss.We will go out to lunch to celebrate our successful negotiation of a new process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/11/04/11408/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 16:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>10/31/08</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/10/31/103108/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've just come back from the groomer's. Pet Smart has a salon. It took longer than we're used to, over three hours and Elwood got the upgraded package, "Top Dog", treatment. He got an oatmeal bath, extra, moisturizers, good for dry skin and his teeth brushed which he apparently liked and tried eating the toothbrush. I was able to get him out of hock for $45. This is more than twice as much as I paid in Lakewood. He looks great. My friend picked me up; I bought coffee and at the café but was treated to soup and sandwich dinner at their house. C makes bread in a bread machine so L took my bread machine back with him after droping me off so that C could check it out. I was never successful at making bread in Jamestown. We'll see what can be done. I've been romised my bread machine back with a loaf of bread Sunday. We'll see what transpires.&lt;br&gt;Meanwile, it was a shirt sleeves day here. Elwood and I went to the library to return books and pick up books. The cassettes are degraded, I think, so I'm reporting as I go. Elwood went past the library driveway and brought me into a construction zone. They're doing the water lines near the library. The dump truck driver came to help. He said he had seen me around. He walked me to the library. If Elwood had done the right thing, we would havenever gotten involved in the construction. On the other hand, we wouldn't know about it and given the driver a chance to stretch his legs. Everything works out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/10/31/103108/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 23:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A.M. Radio</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/09/27/a-m-radio/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been using the FM tuner in my Iriver mp3 player to listen to my NPR station. In Madison, I get Wisconsin Public Radio so there's little local news but some state news. It's not a really powerful radio. I had my boombox sitting on the work station which wasn't good for reception. I brought it into the dining room but it wouldn't work. The batteries were dead. I finally checked it out in the bedroom and the radio worked if plugged in. I brought it back to the dining room. No soap. On a hunch, I threw the switch in the living room. Voila. This particular socket is controlled by the switch. Now the radio is working fine and the Brewers' game is on. It's a Milwaukee station. Two stations away the same game is playing out of Chicago. Not looking good for the Brewers in the 3rd inning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/09/27/a-m-radio/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 21:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pleasant Day</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/09/22/pleasant-day/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday I went out to lunch with my ride and some family members. Not all the people in the "family" are directly related to one another which makes it remarkable that they consider themselves family. I had the opportunity to review a Braille menu which was not only incomplete in the meals offered but some of the words were cut off. The folks were startled that the Braille did not follow the large print. I was surprised they thought it would as they are different sizes. Afterwards, we stopped at the farmer's market at my corner. I was able to pick up some vegetables for the week. The carrots are all knobby and odd sizes which makes them fun. I decided to offer one to Elwood as a treat. I think he was quite shocked about it though he didn't refuse it and went off to enjoy it. After church I got some apples, too, which were from an orchard though how they arrived and what the distribution method was I did not learn. One of my lunch companions offered to go thrift store shopping with me later in the week. We will firm things up at the Wednesday night dinner. One of my Bible study companions came to chat after church. It was nice to recognize a few people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/09/22/pleasant-day/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 09:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>7/27/08</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/27/72708/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given Elwood';s desire for outside time, we went for a walk. We took West Wingra to the corner of South Park, crossed and followed the bike path to Fish Hatchery and then south along Fish Hatchery. Lots of cyclists. One of the things about not being church-connected is you find out what people do on Sunday mornings--shop at the coop and cycle and go to coffee shops so far as I know. We came back to South Park and crossed. It turns out the north bound lane is closed for construction. Lots of stones and dirt. We navigated the crazy intersection at the next corner. I wasn't 100% clear on where we were when Elwood stopped at the coffee shop door. We went in and I had lunch, inquiring how many streets down Olen is. Some consternation. People don't carry this information around with them. But, as I expected, the couple at the next table went outside, looked and came back to report. I also learned the hair "hair cutting place" is on the next corner. Good to know as I need one. We found Olen and the button when someone came along to walk with me across the street because of the construction. We found our way to the grocery store--I was up for going to the corner and making a longer walk but Elwood knows the grocery store so we went there. Then Elwood went exploring. A pair of women rescued us and, with some suggestion of furthering our walk, we made our way home. Elwood was clear about the driveway and the outside door. See, I found it, so it got much congratulations about finding the coffee shop and finding his way back home. His sojourn at the grocery store had to do with dumpsters. Defintely of interest to dogs. It's sticky out there so we were glad to come home to a cooled apartment. I had turned the air on to be ready to receive hot person and dog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/27/72708/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2008 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>7/13/08</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/14/71308/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;J. and Melanie have just left. The goods came today. The poundage was right because there is stuff all over the place. We think the hussle is telling you that you have far less stuff than you really have. I think by a studio they mean a dorm room, etc. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It's been a gorgeous day. Melanie and I left early this morning for the coop. For $10 I got a year's membership as a disabled person. This entitles me to a 10% discount. I bought enough food to already pay for the year's membership. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You can buy shampoo in bulk. By this I don't mean you get a large container. I mean you can buy it by the ounce. You can also purchase a handy container which you can bring and reuse. The pasta is sold this way, too, along with olive oil, rolled oats and honey to name a few items. We brought home coffee in cups made with water-based ink and cheese Danish. Melaniue had scrambled eggs for breakfast. We went for lunch at the local coffee shop which is very friendly. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of the traffic lights has a buzzer to tell you when the walk sign comes on. Elwood has identified the local grocery store. The medical center parking lot is empty on weekends.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The sound proofing isn't the greatest, but the setting is terrific. There's been a nice breeze. I found I had two extra windows, one in the dining area and one in the living room.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Right now there are too many boxes about. Winter clothing and Christmas decorations are already in the storage area which has a wooden floor to get things off the basement floor. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;M, thanks for the notes on the boxes. They were read.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The driver was pleasant and complained about how the truck was packed. He is off to Michigan and then to New Jersey. The dispatcher called to say the driver wouldn t deliver until Sunday because he got caught in traffic in Chicago. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I'm blogging from the phone. The cable box did not arrive so I have to track that down tomorrow. Cell coverage is dodgie on both my network and Melanie's. However, voice mail is received. I'll keep you updated here and hope the internet gets sorted soon. Everyone in Madison has their networks locked down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/14/71308/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 16:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>6/27/08</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/06/27/62708/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elwood and I arrived in Chicago 32 minutes early. We caught up to Patience and Brian. Now we are all sitting around J. and Melanie's table for supper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/06/27/62708/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 02:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2/1/08</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/02/01/2108/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This is a test post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/02/01/2108/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 21:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Around Town</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/02/01/around-town/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the bad windstorm that hit Buffalo and the northern part of the county only made our streets blustery. I used the yacktracks (spelling) for the first time. They go over the bottoms of my boots to help get a secure grip on the sidewalk. It was icy in the morning. I'm getting used to them. It feels like very springy stuff underfoot and I didn't feel quite as stable but I didn't slip.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On the way home the crossing of 3rd treet didn't feel right--too long. I encouraged Elwood to get out of the street and onto the sidewalk. He did, bumping me into a sign. Well, a sign was better than a atractor trailor. We got to the next curb. I was expecting Pine Street which is brick with a long ramp. We weren't there. Hmmm. Where were we? It was cold and the wind was blowing. It was not a pleasant to day to be lost if there is ever a pleasant day to be lost. I decided we must be at the corner of North Main and 2nd on the west side. This meant that when crossing 3rd, Elwood had angled across NOrth Main, too. I mention this not to scare anyone, but to say how grateful I am that Jamestown drivers make it a point not to hit me when I'm walking down the center of the street which has the light. So we made our turn, crossed, went down to Pine, up the hill, crossed Pine and came home. That was done with great aplomb. I always wonder what prompts a dog to make such an error. I sometimes think they are daydreaming or something catches their eye or maybe we just got blown across the street. Of course, this story sounds straight forward and simple. It's not when I don't know for certain that I'm standing at the northwest corner of 2nd and North Main. I could have been on an entirely different street facing another direction. I just acted as if and it worked out just fine. Because of the weather, we didn't take our afternoon walk yesterday but we ventured forth today. I tiink the yacktrax helped a good deal on the river walk. I A great deal of the path is now exposed but there is a patch which is slow to clear. It must be shady there. Elwood considers we are a standard route and he walks it without complaint. We're working on going to the down curb at North Main and not turning left or right to go up or down the hill until I tellhim which way to go. I also pointed out the cut out in the sidewalk that was causing me to go off the walk into the grassline. He avoided that mistake the next time through. Elwood still has difficulty with right hand clearances. In his defense, and he doesn't have much of a case, honestly, he often has to fit through some fairly tight places and I carry a bag in my right arm and tend to have that arm out a bit from my body. However, it's his job to account for everything. His trainer was young and maybe thinner. I actually think he doesn't like tosqueeze himself. However, he doesn't like to be in error so pays attention when I point things out to him. He even did a bit better with not sniffing the people he passed today. In avoiding a nasty piece of sidewalk on the bridge the other day he ran me into the side of the bridge. I hope there is more than the concrete I felt; otherwise, I could have gone over the edge which would not have been pleasant. The river is running but probably very, very cold. Someone asked me the other day how my new dog was working out. I said, "He's learning the ropes." And the other person said, "I thought they came trained." Well, yes, but every trip, every route is its own new adventure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mobile</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/02/01/around-town/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 21:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>