<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about move)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/move.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:n.tesla@example.com"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 18:58:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Walks</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/01/walks-2/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the comments and news. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandra, a busy day after Grace isn't a bad thing. You'll hit your stride soon. I'm looking forward to your journal resuming publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I sat down to the computer to do some work. I ended up dealing with upgrades and system issues. It took me most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night we walked to the local Outpost Coop to buy a few things. Kiwi for breakfast is very good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie keeps saying it's about a mile away. Generally, it's one and a half to two miles away to these locations so we all get a good walk in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elwood is doing very well and identified the driveway on the way home. This is encouraging. He is very quiet during the day. He likes laying on the bedroom rug in the sun and watching me from the doorway while I work at the dining room table. I also suspect he is doing some sort of grieving for friends and places. Dogs do this in their own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is set up for me to visit the apartment and do the paperwork tomorrow so I will have news. Jay still needs some content for the radio show so that is my task to accomplish this week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>move</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/01/walks-2/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 13:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Walks</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/01/walks/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the comments and news. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandra, a busy day after Grace isn't a bad thing. You'll hit your stride soon. I'm looking forward to your journal resuming publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I sat down to the computer to do some work. I ended up dealing with upgrades and system issues. It took me most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night we walked to the local Outpost Coop to buy a few things. Kiwi for breakfast is very good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie keeps saying it's about a mile away. Generally, it's one and a half to two miles away to these locations so we all get a good walk in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elwood is doing very well and identified the driveway on the way home. This is encouraging. He is very quiet during the day. He likes laying on the bedroom rug in the sun and watching me from the doorway while I work at the dining room table. I also suspect he is doing some sort of grieving for friends and places. Dogs do this in their own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is set up for me to visit the apartment and do the paperwork tomorrow so I will have news. Jay still needs some content for the radio show so that is my task to accomplish this week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>move</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/07/01/walks/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 13:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rough Waters</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/06/30/rough-waters/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The movers finally arrive after 5 o'clock Saturday and were very tired. Apparently their last pickup thought they would pack everything and was totally unpacked. Of course, they hadn't contracted for this. I understand they moved everything out, but left a few hinges behind. Fortunately, they will be mailed. They did, however, litter which I will report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My daughter-in-law arrived at work after vacation to discover her boss thought she would be out today and scheduled a meeting for all day tomorrow when we planned to sign the lease. I have emailed the apartment and I hope Wednesday will be okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not n knowing when the stuff will arrive here in Wisconsin is frustrating and a big unsettling. Also missing my daughter-i-law's emails because I have the mesage notification turned off makes me feel a bit incompetent. I am, however, moving forward with some more moving details. All in good time. An interstate move seems very complicated this time though I've done it before. I think it is because I am not closely associated with my things. Maybe life gets more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Melanie's family came for dinner and that was pleasant. J. and I had coffee together at a shop with outdoor tables. I'm also checking into the new desktop computer so that I can check in with Bible study from time to time.    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>move</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/06/30/rough-waters/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 16:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Saturday</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/06/28/saturday/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elwood was still on eastern time this morning. Now that he and I know where his relief area is, this will work well. We took a long walk with J. and Melanie to a local coffee shop where we had lunch outside. Milwaukee prices are very different from Jamestown prices. Next we went to Trader Joe's and to Walgreens. A several mile walk in gorgeous weather. I got a sunburn. Elwood got a workout with many street crossings. He handled everything with aplomb. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned rice noodles have 56 carbs per quarter cup serving. I won't be eating them again very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After numerous phone calls from the driver, my mover arrived at 5:10 p.m. today. It will be longer before my stuff arrives in madison as I had been told. I'm working at making myself scarce around the apartment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elwood is settling in well and getting used to these new arrangements quickly which is a relief. I'm even figuring out the new place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll go Tuesday to sign the lease and see my new digs for the first time. This will help to know what I need to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids helped me pick out a new table, chairs, and computer station. It's a very different style from what I have had before. The chairs, for example, are black microfiber with chrome legs and a lighter wood top on the table with a white computer desk with metal foil. Melanie also found a small cabinet with two drawers in scratch and dent since the computer table has only shelving. We picked up a keyboard shelf to add to it. I'm trying to do simple lines and a new look. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>move</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2008/06/28/saturday/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 00:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>