<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about Org)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/org.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 16:09:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Indentation</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/23/indentation/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have been writing my Nanowrimo Prep document. This is a series of
headings and several nested lists along with lengthy paragraphs either
under a heading or under one of my list items.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This sounds straight forward enough but I have run into problems
largely because I didn't fully grasp how Org thought of indentations.
This was fully revealed to me when I exported my document to html.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I was totally baffled. The web page didn't look like what I was
writing. To solve this, I started editing the html document and
converted back to org using pandoc. The conversion wasn't perfect, but
good enough to clue me in.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Did I mention that actually writing in html is &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; difficult?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you want to see your document as a web page, type:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
c-c c-e h o
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This will not only convert your document, but open it in a web page
where you can easily see what is going on. Using a screen reader, the
headlines are identified as well as the lists, the number of items in
a list and whether you are going into or coming out of a nested list.
Another helpful clue is that the headings are numbered (unless you
have turned this off globally). Finally, the list items are numbered
(if you are using numbered lists) and you can see how Org is thinking
of them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Indent Everything&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, maybe not everything, but even paragraphs under a heading or a
list item should be indented to see the relationship.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes Org resisted this. I had a paragraph at the left hand margin
and I want to shift it left three spaces. Org couldn't do that for me
so I had to manually indent line after line. Auto-fill couldn't do it
either.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If your paragraph is long, Emacspeak will prompt you if you want to
"read this long line?" Annoying, but just press 'n' and then perform
one action. Emacspeak will ask you again. Again press "n" and perform
that action.    
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once you have your paragraph at the right indentation, move to the
beginning of the line and press "m-q" to reflow the paragraph. Now
that pesky "read long line?" prompt will go away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you are moving things around, adding and subtracting list items, go
to the top of the list and press "c-c c-c" to renumber it. This will
maintain your sanity somewhat. It will also show you where the
numbering is inconsistent. At this point, you can track down the
problem in your formatting.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Happy writing. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Org</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/23/indentation/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 15:52:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Writing a Book Part 1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have started to write a book which gathers together some of my
previous posts on Org and then fleshes out the material.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org524d430" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org524d430"&gt;Setting Up a To-do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org524d430"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I first set up a to-do to track my progress. I am modifying the steps
as I go, but here is what it currently looks like:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
* STARTED Write a series of articles on getting organized with org mode [5/10]

     1. [X] Gather all files into a new git repository
     2. [X] Create a landing page for the ebook
     3. [X] Write an outline for my getting organized articles
     4. [X] Integrate blog posts into this outline
     5. [X] Write a script to convert .org files to .md files and copy
        them to the book directory
     6. [ ] Write the book. Chapter by Chapter goes below.
     7. [ ] Publish the ebook
     8. [ ] Upload the ebook to archive.org
     9. [ ] Update the download link on the landing page.
     10. [ ] Write a blog post announcing the book.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have checked off have of the items, but it is the easy stuff I've
checked off. So far I only have listed one items for writing the book
though I plan on adding check boxes underneath this item so I can
check off each chapter. The final check box is to review the entire
book and make any necessary corrections.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"STARTED" is a to-do state that I developed for my projects. More on
that when I discuss "TODO" in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org0fe9fe6" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org0fe9fe6"&gt;Setting Things Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org0fe9fe6"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up the git repository was very straight forward on &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.
Then I looked over my blog and copied the posts that applied into
that directory and updated the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I then wrote a landing page for the book. The idea of a landing page
is to have the potential reader focus on your book and the &lt;b&gt;Call to
Action&lt;/b&gt; which is for you, the reader, to click on the "buy" button.
My page is quite simple and does not have a "Download" button yet
since the book is not finished. You can look at it &lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/living-my-life-in-plain-text-page.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3d00dd0" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3d00dd0"&gt;Outlining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3d00dd0"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I then set about putting together an outline to help me think about
what the book should cover. This is not set in stone. More chapters
may appear and the ones listed here may disappear. This is what it
currently looks like in Org markup.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** Table of Contents
** Introduction -- what this book hopes to accomplish
** Thinking About Doing
** A Few Quick Notes on Orgmode Markup
** Setting up your Initial Emacs Configuration for Org
** Setting up a Calendar
** Seeing Your Calendar as an Agenda
** Making a To-do List
** How Deep Should You Go?
*** To-do Checkboxes
*** To-do Keywords
*** Priorities
** Revisiting the Agenda
*** Helpful keys in the Agenda -- archiving, saving, changing status
*** Seeing the Agenda on STartup
*** Remember to Refresh
** Capturing Information
*** Deciding what to Capture
** To Refile or Not to Refile
** Writing in Orgmode
** Exporting and Publishing in Orgmode
** Keeping Track of Expenses
** References
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org7542d41" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org7542d41"&gt;Promotion and Demotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org7542d41"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In looking this over, the first thing I want to do is change the
headline level. I need to move everything up one level so that heading
3s become heading2s and heading2s become heading1s
What I want to do is called promotion. I highlighted the text, went to
the org menu and found "promote" under the "edit structure" menu item.
There is a shortcut key you can use if you do this often enough to
remember it "m-s-left". You can also demote items "m-s-right"..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org9330537" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org9330537"&gt;Changing Headlines into Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org9330537"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can change headlines into lists and lists into headlines. I
changed my outline headings into an unordered list of to-do items by
highlighting them and then applying the command "c-c -". That's "c-c
hyphen". The "-" (hyphen) gives you the clue. The asterisks "*" are
replaced wit a hyphen "-". You can go the other way by using "c-c *" (asterisk).  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orge7e03ea" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orge7e03ea"&gt;Making an Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orge7e03ea"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orge78c6d3" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orge78c6d3"&gt;What Didn't Work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orge78c6d3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then I investigated how to make an epub. Pandoc can do this. One of
the examples I found showed how to put a bunch of markdown files in a
directory and then turn them into an ebook. Great, I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I tried to use org-publish to do this but I could not get a batch
transformation of all org files. I've tried this in the past and the
markdown export function still hangs. I think I had 30 buffers open wantiiting
for something. I have no idea what   
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I found this script on the &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org/faqs.html"&gt;pandoc site&lt;/a&gt; and modified it for my purpose:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
#!/bin/bash
# Convert all org files in a directory to markdown
# This script is to convert and move markdown into the book folder

for f in *.org;
do pandoc "$f" -s -o "${f%.org}.md";
done
mv *.md book/
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then I discovered I would have to include every filename in the
directory in my pandoc command. That seemed more trouble than it was
worth as the moment so I will just write in one file and perhaps split
it out at the end so that I can update it more easily. We'll see.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org66ebbf8" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org66ebbf8"&gt;What Did work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org66ebbf8"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had to add some YML stuff to the beginning of my file:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
---
title: Living My Life in Plain Text
author: Rill Woolnough
rights: Creative Commons Attribution Non-commercial ShareAlike
---
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's the pandoc command I am using:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
pandoc -o book.epub book.org --toc --toc-depth=3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org568499d" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org568499d"&gt;Reading the Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org568499d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So how to read it? Enter emacspeak. It uses the eww browser to render
the book. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
m-x     emacspeak-epub-open  ret
enter the path to the book ret
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Because Firefox is my default browser, the book opens there. There is
single letter navigation to move around in the book as if you are in a
regular web page. alt-f4 closes the book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3191d93" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3191d93"&gt;Back to Work!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3191d93"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now I'm going back to writing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Org</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 17:17:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Checkboxes</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/02/using-checkboxes/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I wrote about
&lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/28/recurring-tasks-in-orgmode/"&gt;Recurring Tasks in Orgmode&lt;/a&gt; previously. Once I had this to-do working properly,
I went onto the next task. I wanted to list my ideas for articles and
bigger writing projects. In my opinion, I did not need to set this all
up as a big list of to-dos. That certainly becomes overwhelming to
me.I might just stop writing altogether because the ideas keep coming
but the time and patience to write them may not be available at the
moment. I do
want to be sure I have a stash of ideas to choose from when I am able
to sit down and write out a complete article.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I created a file name "ideas.org". I inserted three headings:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
* Writing Ideas Big and Small
** Blog Ideas [/]
** Bigger WRiting Projects [/]

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You may have noticed that at the end of the second level headings
there are two square brackets "[]" enclosing a slash "/". More on this
later.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgacf951f" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgacf951f"&gt;Organizing the list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgacf951f"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At first I thought I would just write a list like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- smart quotess and other typography
- less than shortcuts in orgmode
- Braile pack at public museum
- photo op with Nick
- a walk in the park with Nick
- using org capture
- Using checkboxes in org

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then I thought about using checkboxes so I could check them off as I
went. Now this section of the file looks like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- [ ] smart quotess and other typography
- [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
- [ ] Braile pack at public museum
- [ ] photo op with Nick
- [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
- [ ] using org capture
- [ ] Using checkboxes in org

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Who knows, you might even see some of these articles in the future!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org525edff" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org525edff"&gt;Why Use Checkboxes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org525edff"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Why use checkboxes? After all, I could simply delete the item from the
file once I published it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It's a good point. I decided to try this methodology just to see how I
liked it and for two other reasons:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would let me know how I was doing at keeping up with my ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would let me know if I needed to be thinking more about writing
opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It seems to me that a writer is stuck here: Coming up with ideas and
getting them written.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org6e721c1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org6e721c1"&gt;Using the Checkboxes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org6e721c1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To check off an item, press "c-c c-c" on that line. Then you have:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
:- [X] Using checkboxes in org
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's what the heading now looks like:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
** Blog Ideas [1/7]

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If I turn the "/" (slash) into a percent sign (%) it looks like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
:** Blog Ideas &lt;code&gt;[14%]&lt;/code&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If I feel ambitious, I can delete these lines or I can sort them so
that all the unchecked boxes are together.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgc1a4de7" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgc1a4de7"&gt;Sorting Lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgc1a4de7"&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Type "m-x sort-lines". All the checked off items will be gathered
together at the end of the list. The items appear in alphabetical
order.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- [ ] Braile pack at public museum
- [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
- [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
- [ ] photo op with Nick
- [ ] smart quotess and other typography
   - [ ] using org capture
- [X] Using checkboxes in org 

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This list now is in a different order than the way I originally
wrote it down. I can read through it until I come to an item with a
checkbox. I know there are no more new items.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If I want to sort in reverse order, I type: "c-u m-x sort-lines".
Here is what I now have:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
- [X] Using checkboxes in org
- [ ] using org capture
- [ ] smart quotess and other typography
- [ ] photo op with Nick
- [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
- [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
- [ ] Braile pack at public museum

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I don't think I will use this ordering unless I need a confidence
boost. I would have to go past everything I've already done.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Org</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/02/using-checkboxes/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 15:32:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>