<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about outings)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/outings.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 01:10:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Cheese making</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/26/cheese-making/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is a school holiday. My friends, their niece and their cousin's wife came to make cheese. We made two kinds of cheese, mozzarella and lemon cheese. It was quite exciting. We even had milk from a local dairy 20 miles north of Madison. We will visit one day as their is an artisan cheese maker nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the cheese making was done, we went to Ian's for pizza.Although Ian's can make you a pie, they typically sell by the slice and have 20 varieties to choose from. They are happy to run them down for you as you move around the display area. Combinations of vegetables, meats and fruit capped by their best-seller: macaroni and cheese pizza. This is a white pizza with elbow macaronis. I had a slice of this and a spinach-roasted pepper-and-portobella mushroom slice. This latter was a bit wet and I would choose something else another time. The cousin met us there for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward we stopped by a popcorn store. Like the pizza joint, they sell all kinds of popcorn. Friends bought several kinds including a rainbow popcorn with raspberry, blueberry, grape, lime and vanilla popcorn mixed together. Reviews from the back seat varied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also went to St. Vinnie's where I found more containers for bulk items and some plates to match my table--a whole box-full for $12. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another stop was at the coop for a few items I forgot and to check on the membership requirements as they are changing. I need to show some paperwork for a special membership. I will be able to do so next month after my hair cut downtown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I brought the Trekker Breeze with me to mark more places of interest. K was able to wear it on her glove. This did not work for me. I tried attaching it to my sleeve with a little more success. The purpose has got to go. I can only manage two things and Elwood is one of them. &lt;a href="//elwood/"&gt;Elwood&lt;/a&gt;, for his part, enjoyed the attention but was very, very bouncy and so needed much correction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had sighted assistance for a computer problem support and I are working together on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a good day. Currently, two loads of wash are in the dryer.     &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>outings</category><category>trekker breeze</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/26/cheese-making/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 00:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doings Today</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/12/doings-today-2/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today Elwood went to Pet Smart for his quarterly top dog treatment. I went to the cosmetology department at MATC for a pedicure, manicure, eyebrow waxing  and hair cut. This is a good plan. I will have the same person cut my hair next time which is good because we are trying to straighten everything out from some poor hair cuts previously. I get to listen in on what the instructors tell the student and who knows, maybe I can learn something to tell another operator. I'm hoping the instructors learn my hair. I was also able to get Elwood a new bone and his food on sale as well as get a regular customer discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I brought my GPS with me. I forgot to turn it on at first and it takes a good 20 minutes sometimes to find the GPS signal, but when it did I could listen in as we drove around. My friends made certain I could landmark everywhere we went and gave me exact names. I even have their house marked.
What is very cool about traveling this way is that I learned where the West Town Mall is, that Target is nearby and that Pet Smart and other places are near where the kids looked at an apartment for me. They decided it was a car-friendly area, not a pedestrian-friendly area. We all figured out it was far out of town.
I would not have known all of this if I had left the GPS home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had it on when my friend brought me home. We were stopping off at the library to pick up my books so I won't have to go anywhere tomorrow when the deep freeze will be upon us. I knew where we were and to say where to turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elwood got a red bow to wear out of the spa. He showed more interest in a new bone and chewed happily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate in a nice restaurant with numerous soup choices. They prepare all their soups gluten-free, adding noodles or rice as a GF alternative when the soup is served. Must keep the noodles and rice from getting gummy, too. I had French garden with basil on top and wonderful crusty bread and butter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had a chance to stop at a second-hand store. I found a canister for Willie Street Coop bulk items and some warm tops including a purple tunic made of  Italian yarn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blindness</category><category>outings</category><category>technology</category><category>trekker breeze</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/12/doings-today-2/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 02:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doings Today</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/12/doings-today/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today Elwood went to Pet Smart for his quarterly top dog treatment. I went to the cosmetology department at MATC for a pedicure, manicure, eyebrow waxing  and hair cut. This is a good plan. I will have the same person cut my hair next time which is good because we are trying to straighten everything out from some poor hair cuts previously. I get to listen in on what the instructors tell the student and who knows, maybe I can learn something to tell another operator. I'm hoping the instructors learn my hair. I was also able to get Elwood a new bone and his food on sale as well as get a regular customer discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I brought my GPS with me. I forgot to turn it on at first and it takes a good 20 minutes sometimes to find the GPS signal, but when it did I could listen in as we drove around. My friends made certain I could landmark everywhere we went and gave me exact names. I even have their house marked.
What is very cool about traveling this way is that I learned where the West Town Mall is, that Target is nearby and that Pet Smart and other places are near where the kids looked at an apartment for me. They decided it was a car-friendly area, not a pedestrian-friendly area. We all figured out it was far out of town.
I would not have known all of this if I had left the GPS home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had it on when my friend brought me home. We were stopping off at the library to pick up my books so I won't have to go anywhere tomorrow when the deep freeze will be upon us. I knew where we were and to say where to turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elwood got a red bow to wear out of the spa. He showed more interest in a new bone and chewed happily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate in a nice restaurant with numerous soup choices. They prepare all their soups gluten-free, adding noodles or rice as a GF alternative when the soup is served. Must keep the noodles and rice from getting gummy, too. I had French garden with basil on top and wonderful crusty bread and butter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had a chance to stop at a second-hand store. I found a canister for Willie Street Coop bulk items and some warm tops including a purple tunic made of  Italian yarn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blindness</category><category>outings</category><category>technology</category><category>trekker breeze</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2009/01/12/doings-today/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 02:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>