<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about Reflection)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/reflection.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 20:52:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Psalm 64</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/psalm-64/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have been trying to read a psalm every day. My Old Testament
professor Dr. Robinson said it would change my life. He said that
twenty years ago (that's a scary thought in and of itself). I've never
succeeded at doing this, but it's never too late to give it a shot. I
would read all the psalms twice through in one year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I've been suggesting we read a psalm at the end of our Bible study on
Thursdays. I don't do it every week, but it turns out one of the
participants doesn't like the psalms. I realized that reading one
every week allows us to work through all 150 psalms over time (three
years or so) without getting bogged down in the book of psalms. That
would make things easier for the participant who doesn't like them.
Someone is marking them off as we go.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is a long introduction to reading Psalm 64. I started at Psalm 61
because that is the psalm we read last Thursday and it seemed to be a
good place to start. The problem of embarking on such a task is that
I've read Psalm 1 a lot and never gotten very far after that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I can't remember ever reading Psalm 64 before. No doubt I have, but
nothing stood out to mean. This morning, however, in the wake of the
terrible shootings at El Paso and Youngstown, I couldn't help thinking of
all those bullets or, as the psalmist put it, arrows. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
David is talking about words, not literal weapons, but it doesn't much matter in the
context of the psalm. Behind the bullets were evil words. And evil
words and hatred are at the crux of the problem in this country. It
there weren't so many evil words flying about like arrows, people
shopping on a Saturday morning for school supplies or going out for a
fun-filled evening wouldn't be dead–terrible! Unspeakable evil!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I take comfort in verse 8:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="verse"&gt;
Their own tongues shall ruin them.&lt;br&gt;
All who see them will shake their heads.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://worldenglishbible.org"&gt;World English Bible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Reflection</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/05/psalm-64/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 20:07:43 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>