<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about Sermon)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/sermon.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 19:16:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Listening for Jesus</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/19/listening-for-jesus/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I preached this sermon at the Common Table service at First Baptist
Madison on May 22, 2016. In that format, I had slides with the
Scripture readings which I included in the sermon. I have modified
this form of my homily to make more sense as an article. It may well
be that it was a part of a series on listening and being heard.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I am speaking to you today in the name of Jesus. Amen.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In his email this week, Jason called me our resident theologian. I'm going to claim this title and talk to you today about the Trinity.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now that half the congregation has left and the rest of you have pulled out your phones and are catching up on Facebook or Snap Chatting your friends, let me tell you that the Trinity makes it possible for us to listen for Jesus' voice today. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
From the beginning, the Bible speaks of God's voice. I'm going to go through some examples rather quickly. The Scripture quotations are from my new favorite translation: The Common English Bible.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When God began to create the heavens and the earth— the earth was
without shape or form, it was dark over the deep sea, and God’s wind
swept over the waters— God said, “Let there be light.” And so light
appeared. – Genesis 1:1-3
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the beginning was the Word and the Word was with God and the Word was God.&lt;br&gt;
The Word became flesh and made his home among us. We have seen his glory, glory like that of a father’s only son, full of grace and truth – John 1:1, 14
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class="verse"&gt;
He is our God,&lt;br&gt;
    and we are the people of his pasture,&lt;br&gt;
    the sheep in his hands&lt;br&gt;
If only you would listen to his voice right now! – Psalm 95:7&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My sheep listen to my voice. I know them and they follow me. – John 10:27
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then the church throughout Judea, Galilee, and Samaria enjoyed a time
of peace. God strengthened the church, and its life was marked by
reverence for the Lord. Encouraged by the Holy Spirit, the church continued to grow in numbers. – Acts 9:31 Common English Bible (CEB)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So the church throughout all Judea and Galilee and Samaria had peace
and was being built up. And walking in the fear of the Lord and in the
comfort of the Holy Spirit, it multiplied. – Acts 9:31 English Standard Version (ESV)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I gave you the verse from Acts in two translations to show you some different ways of speaking about what the Holy Spirit does: 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encourage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comfort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The author of Acts paints an idyllic picture–one we all hope for in our church and often despair of. There is:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;peace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comfort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encouragement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;increase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Is this something that only happened long ago and 21st century Christians in Madison, Wisconsin have no access to this strengthening and encouragement?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The good news: We have the same access and can have the same experience as those who have gone before us. The church described in Acts can be our church today.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
“I have much more to say to you, but you can’t handle it now. However,
when the Spirit of Truth comes, he will guide you in all truth. He
won’t speak on his own, but will say whatever he hears and will
proclaim to you what is to come. He will glorify me, because he will
take what is mine and proclaim it to you. Everything that the Father
has is mine. That’s why I said that the Spirit takes what is mine and
will proclaim it to you. – John 16:12-15
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So here we have the Trinity at work:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is mighty to save us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus tells and shows us who God is and what God does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Holy Spirit enables us to show and tell others about Jesus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The Work of the Holy Spirit
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guiding or leading us so we don't feel we're alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reminding us what Jesus said and did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prompting us into new ways of thinking and acting on Jesus' behalf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encouraging us when we become disheartened and dispirited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So how does this work?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ways to Listen for Jesus
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Energy   
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Have you noticed how much energy is in this room? The Holy Spirit is here, enlivening each one of us, igniting our enthusiasm for our work together.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Preaching  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hear Jesus' voice through the message every week. Participate in the discussion afterwards. Talk to someone about it during our fellowship time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Scripture  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Read the Bible. NoThe Common English Bible is written for a seventh grader. If you don't understand what you are reading, (The Ethiopian eunuch didn't know and I certainly didn't when I started), ask someone in this room. If that person can't help you, keep asking until you get an answer that makes sense to you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Gather  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Listening for Jesus is not just a solo activity.  It is a communal one, too. We don't just gather together to hang out, but we gather to interact with one another and listen for Jesus through other people. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Pray  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have ways for you to pray at our tables along the wall. There are word prayers all over the internet if you can't find the words yourself. Ask someone to pray with you during our prayer time, afterwards or as an ongoing prayer partner.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sing  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Learn the songs we sing here by heart. I'm sure you can find them on YouTube or your favorite streaming music service.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Your Turn
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That's what I've got. Now it's time for you to speak.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Sermon</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/19/listening-for-jesus/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 02:01:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>