<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Web Site (Posts about Writing)</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/categories/writing.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 19:02:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Writing a Book Part 1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have started to write a book which gathers together some of my
previous posts on Org and then fleshes out the material.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgde47f8a" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgde47f8a"&gt;Setting Up a To-do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgde47f8a"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I first set up a to-do to track my progress. I am modifying the steps
as I go, but here is what it currently looks like:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
* STARTED Write a series of articles on getting organized with org mode [5/10]

    1. [X] Gather all files into a new git repository
    2. [X] Create a landing page for the ebook
    3. [X] Write an outline for my getting organized articles
    4. [X] Integrate blog posts into this outline
    5. [X] Write a script to convert .org files to .md files and copy
       them to the book directory
    6. [ ] Write the book. Chapter by Chapter goes below.
    7. [ ] Publish the ebook
    8. [ ] Upload the ebook to archive.org
    9. [ ] Update the download link on the landing page.
    10. [ ] Write a blog post announcing the book.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have checked off have of the items, but it is the easy stuff I've
checked off. So far I only have listed one items for writing the book
though I plan on adding check boxes underneath this item so I can
check off each chapter. The final check box is to review the entire
book and make any necessary corrections.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"STARTED" is a to-do state that I developed for my projects. More on
that when I discuss "TODO" in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3efe7ae" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3efe7ae"&gt;Setting Things Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org3efe7ae"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up the git repository was very straight forward on &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.
Then I looked over my blog and copied the posts that applied into
that directory and updated the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I then wrote a landing page for the book. The idea of a landing page
is to have the potential reader focus on your book and the &lt;b&gt;Call to
Action&lt;/b&gt; which is for you, the reader, to click on the "buy" button.
My page is quite simple and does not have a "Download" button yet
since the book is not finished. You can look at it &lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/living-my-life-in-plain-text-page.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org8e51430" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org8e51430"&gt;Outlining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org8e51430"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I then set about putting together an outline to help me think about
what the book should cover. This is not set in stone. More chapters
may appear and the ones listed here may disappear. This is what it
currently looks like in Org markup.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
#+begin&lt;sub&gt;example&lt;/sub&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;* Table of Contents
 *&lt;/b&gt; Introduction – what this book hopes to accomplish
 &lt;b&gt;* Thinking About Doing
 *&lt;/b&gt; A Few Quick Notes on Orgmode Markup
 &lt;b&gt;* Setting up your Initial Emacs Configuration for Org
 *&lt;/b&gt; Setting up a Calendar
 &lt;b&gt;* Seeing Your Calendar as an Agenda
 *&lt;/b&gt; Making a To-do List
 ** How Deep Should You Go?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgab69e6e" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orgab69e6e"&gt;To-do Checkboxes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org4c000a8" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org4c000a8"&gt;To-do Keywords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgaf2118d" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orgaf2118d"&gt;Priorities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orgaf2118d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
** Revisiting the Agenda
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgec3d19d" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orgec3d19d"&gt;Helpful keys in the Agenda – archiving, saving, changing status&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgbea41a2" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orgbea41a2"&gt;Seeing the Agenda on STartup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org3cab928" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org3cab928"&gt;Remember to Refresh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org3cab928"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
** Capturing Information
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org2a4cfd7" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org2a4cfd7"&gt;Deciding what to Capture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org2a4cfd7"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;* To Refile or Not to Refile
 *&lt;/b&gt; Writing in Orgmode
 &lt;b&gt;* Exporting and Publishing in Orgmode
 *&lt;/b&gt; Keeping Track of Expenses
 ** References
#+end&lt;sub&gt;example&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org4c5766d" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org4c5766d"&gt;Promotion and Demotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org4c5766d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In looking this over, the first thing I want to do is change the
headline level. I need to move everything up one level so that heading
3s become heading2s and heading2s become heading1s
What I want to do is called promotion. I highlighted the text, went to
the org menu and found "promote" under the "edit structure" menu item.
There is a shortcut key you can use if you do this often enough to
remember it "m-s-left". You can also demote items "m-s-right"..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org26c639a" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org26c639a"&gt;Changing Headlines into Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org26c639a"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can change headlines into lists and lists into headlines. I
changed my outline headings into an unordered list of to-do items by
highlighting them and then applying the command "c-c -". That's "c-c
hyphen". The "-" (hyphen) gives you the clue. The asterisks "*" are
replaced wit a hyphen "-". You can go the other way by using "c-c *" (asterisk).  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org24f99c2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org24f99c2"&gt;Making an Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org24f99c2"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org01091f2" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org01091f2"&gt;What Didn't Work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org01091f2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then I investigated how to make an epub. Pandoc can do this. One of
the examples I found showed how to put a bunch of markdown files in a
directory and then turn them into an ebook. Great, I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I tried to use org-publish to do this but I could not get a batch
transformation of all org files. I've tried this in the past and the
export function still hangs. I think I had 30 buffers open wantiiting
for something. I have no idea what  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
#!/bin/bash
# Convert all org files in a directory to markdown
# This script is to convert and move markdown into the book folder

for f in *.org;
do pandoc "$f" -s -o "${f%.org}.md";
done
mv *.md book/
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then I discovered I would have to include every filename in the
directory in my pandoc command. That seemed more trouble than it was
worth as the moment so I will just write in one file and perhaps split
it out at the end so that I can update it more easily. We'll see.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org60e295b" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org60e295b"&gt;What Did work for MeSo I found this script on the &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org/faqs.html"&gt;pandoc site&lt;/a&gt; and modified it for my purpose:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org60e295b"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So here's the pandoc command I am using:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
pandoc -o book.epub book.org --toc --toc-depth=3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org11cdfcf" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org11cdfcf"&gt;Reading the Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org11cdfcf"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So how to read it? Enter emacspeak. It uses the eww browser to render
the book. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
m-x     emacspeak-epub-open  ret
enter the path to the book ret
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Because Firefox is my default browser, the book opens there. There is
single letter navigation to move around in the book as if you are in a
regular web page. alt-f4 closes the book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org54d3ff6" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org54d3ff6"&gt;Back to Work!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org54d3ff6"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now I'm going back to writing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Org</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/13/writing-a-book-part-1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 17:17:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Library</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/28/in-the-library/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Picture this. Ronnie, our intrepid heroine, is
sitting in the great library of the wizards in the heart of Magic
City. (I know. I know. These names are not very imaginative and need
changing, but it is the best I can do right now.) Anyway, she is
sitting in the library not because she wants to be there but because
she is compelled to be there. The Tribunal of All Wizards (Is this a
better name?) has sentenced her to serve there for some unspecified
length of time. She goes to the library at the pleasure of the Grand
Mistress of Wizards who doesn't like her to begin with. Ronnie is
fulfilling her sentence for the misuse of magic which caused the death
of her mentor, Grand Master Awk.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Although Ronnie is unhappy that she must remain in the Magic Lands for
perhaps the rest of her life, she makes the best of being confined to
the library and her living quarters for most of every day. As
imprisonments go in the inhabited galaxy, it is a very lenient
sentence.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The wizards did not come up with this punishment without
reason. Ronnie has shown an aptitude for magic. The wizards hope she
can learn to read and understand the books stored in the library which
they cannot even open. Ronnie thinks their hope in her is
misplaced. Even if she can open a book, why do they think she can read
an ancient script and make sense of it. She does not possess these
skills.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Neverthe less, she goes to the library and tries to open every book on
every shelf. There are many thousands of books.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then one day Ronnie lugs a very large volume to the library table by
the window. It has a pleasant view of a garden. She sets the tome
down. What else can she possibly call the book but a tome. It is
dusty. Its binding shows much wear. She wonders just how old this book
is and what sort of a book this is. There are no pictures on the
covers. The script on its binding is beautiful and perhaps contains
grains of precious gems. This is not her expertise either but the
script seems to sparkle.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
With no expectations at all, she tries to open the book. And it
opens.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ronnie gasps. The librarian, working at his desk across the room,
looks up to see the book open and hurries over.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Can you read it?" he asks rather breathlessly.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Can you see the pictures?" Ronnie asks him.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"The page is blank," the librarian responds, puzzled.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"No, it is not," Ronnie says. "It is a beautifully done star chart."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
They stand in silence. Ronnie can see it while the librarian cannot.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"A star chart of what?" the librarian finally asks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"I don't know," Ronnie says. "I would need a modern star chart and a
way to evaluate procession and drift. I don't recognize any of these
stars, but I am not from around this part of the galactic arm. The
constellations look all wrong to me."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Can you copy the chart?" the librarian asks quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Let's see if I can," Ronnie says.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then she smiles. "If this is a map to treasure, I claim it by virtue
of being able to read the map."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The librarian does not see the humor in her claim but hurries away to
get paper and writing implements. He also calls the Grand Mistress and
she comes to hover over Ronnie's shoulder.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After Ronnie's crude representation of the beautiful chart and much
discussion, the Tribunal corrects the star chart for this time
period. They show it to Ronnie.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"It's Planet X," she says, pointing to a particular
constellation. I've been there."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In an earlier unpublished adventure, she and Captain Star Runner visited this
forbidden planet with disastrous results. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Ronnie Camberwell</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/28/in-the-library/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 01:23:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>No Camp Nanowrimo This Month</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/04/no-camp-nanowrimo-this-month/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I was going to participate in &lt;a href="https://www.campnanowrimo.org/"&gt;Camp Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; this year. I like bbbsetting a low writing goal and meeting it. Call it childish if you like, but positive reinforcement is fun.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But I wanted to do something more than just write a first draft and so I was leery of making a commitment I couldn't keep. Again, seeing a congratulatory message on my screen is quite satisfying.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's what I really want to do:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit my Kearsarge novel. I wrote it as part of &lt;a href="https://www.nanowrimo.org/"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; some time ago and have never finished an edit. I would like to be able to give it to an editor and create an ebook out of it with a cover and everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish Kearsarge to my &lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; site with each chapter as a separate web page linked together. (Right now, I don't know how to do this. I am refreshing my knowledge of orgmode and learning new features.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish writing my memoir piece on Chance so that Cindy can look it over before I send it off to Joy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have already set up &lt;a href="https://www.getnikola.com/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt; to deploy my blog and associated pages to &lt;a href="https://www.github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/07/04/no-camp-nanowrimo-this-month/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 15:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Magic is Difficult</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/01/07/magic-is-difficult/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have really struggled with writing my next Ronnie Camberwell mystery. I was so pleased with myself about exploring magic, but magic has proved to be difficult. Magic has a cost and although I have figured out what the cost is to Ronnie as a result of her careless attitude toward magic, I cannot figure out the cost of magic to the wizard on an ongoing basis. The wizards are just gifted with the ability to perform magic and beyond that, I don't know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've explored the political consequences and that doesn't seem to hold water. Exile would break a society apart. Inherited magic doesn't make sense either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I don't have a good reason for wizards to have the ability to do magic to hang out together in the Magic Lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my mind, the Magic Lands feel very medieval. Perhaps this is just a trope. On the other hand, I have always felt there is something cinister about the place, as if it itself is held fast by a very powerful spell. Who does the work around here? Are they slaves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is just no energy or enthusiasm to write this story.  I might have to recast it and I started to do this by introducing Captain Star Runner into the plot line. I want to develop something which involves these two characters to write regularly this winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Captain Star Runner</category><category>Ronnie Camberwell</category><category>Writing</category><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/01/07/magic-is-difficult/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 06:08:02 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>