<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Rill Online</title>
    <description>Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/Rill&quot;&gt;@Rill on Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 15:44:28 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 15:44:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At last! I know what is happening at the Musical Mountains Mine and how the situation is corrected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ronnie interrupts Roop while he is refreshing the spell which controls the power transfer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He attacks her and Grand Master Awk who comes to her aid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ronnie kills Roop in self defense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before he dies, Grand Master Awk has Ronnie enhance his recasting of the power transfer spell in order to redirect it back to its original path.
The nature of the spell is still hazy, but I think I now have something to work with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is both a credit to Grand Master Awk’s tenacity and dedication that he was able to channel Ronnie’s innate magical abilities to recast the spell. Wounded herself, Ronnie’s final trust of Grand Master Awk allows her to allow him to do this for the greater good. It counts heavily in her favor at her trial later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It still remains to be known if Roop was working alone or whether an additional wizard was involved. Roop is not able, according to the Tribunal, to have cast the initial spell. Questions remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ronnie comes away thinking the Tribunal should have diagnosed the problem at the mine much earlier. They thought someone was pilfering mine assets, not diverting power. Since the mine assets are needed in the war effort, a proper detective was needed and as Ronnie had both detective credentials and the right security clearances, she was a logical choice. Her inexperience with magic, however, posed a serious barrier to her discovery of the problem and resulted in Grand Master Awk’s death indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 15:43:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/25/at-last-i.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/25/at-last-i.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Crazy day today. Couldn’t sleep last night so did some listening. Eventually fell asleep. Slept through my Echo alarm. Woke up late. Took Nick out and hurried through breakfast. While in the shower, one of my friends from Bible study called. Did I want a ride question I sure did. Set that up. Enriching Bible study. Decided to get a ride home as no one was available to go To lunch. Couldn’t find my Bluetooth connector for my phone and hearing aid. Dashed off to my salon appointment. When I went around the corner on KK, no sidewalk. No one answered me when I shouted out to people around a truck. Earbuds? Too much noise? Indifferent?. Went back around Collectivo and across Smith. Crossed South Graham. Nick hung a right. Went with that. I think we went through several alleyways and across the street. Eventually, Nick worked his way back to KK and back to the salon. What a day! And the Bluetooth connector? It was already on my shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 19:07:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/19/crazy-day-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/20/crazy-day-today.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Safety</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I made a step forward in finding ways to protect myself. I have made a pact with a steady parishioner at my church. I will be in text contact with her every Sunday morning. If I say I am coming to church but I don’t show up, my contact will take steps to find me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To facilitate my accountability I have set up a recurringreminder to text my contact every Sunday morning concerning my plans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 15:42:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/16/today-i-made.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/16/today-i-made.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Where is Planet X</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to write one of the books in my Magic Lands series. I’ve started the first book and I’m excited about a second book which I have started to plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series is based on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://nanowrimo.org&quot;&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; novel from  2013 or 2014. That’s a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went back to the beginning and I am doing a very rough editing job on &lt;em&gt;Behind Enemy Lines&lt;/em&gt; which features both Detective Ronnie Camberwell and Captain Star Runner narrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My characters are in a fairly new to them part of Space which calls itself the Primary Zone. (It’s Primary because all the people think of themselves as primary.) There is a lot of ancient history, a variety of peoples and a large canvas to create a history of how the different empires interacted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s the problem: One of the races is missing.  Where they go? Can they be found? Are they coming back? What was their relation to the other founding empires?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, I am finding out, what part of space did they occupy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specific question I am wrestling with right now is where is Planet X? Is it in the Magic Lands or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought it was. But that begs the question: If it is magical now, why wasn’t it magical way back when? And if it is not in the Magic Lands, which makes loads more sense, where is it? How near to the Magic Lands is it? How near to everything and everyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t be concerned about all this underlying stuff except I am uncovering a rough history of the region and it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:21:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/13/where-is-planet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/14/where-is-planet.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>What a Mess!</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mirroring my &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/&quot;&gt;Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; site created some unexpected results. My &lt;a href=&quot;https://rillonline.github.io/&quot;&gt;rillonline.github.io&lt;/a&gt; site was entirely replaced to look identical to &lt;a href=&quot;http://rill.micro.blog/&quot;&gt;rill.micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;. I had a few bad moments with &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; and lots of emails from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, but I think this will be all right in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 15:00:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/13/what-a-mess.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/09/13/what-a-mess.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Bus Break</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed to take a bit of a break from traveling by bus. Now that I have had this bus vacation, Nick and I traveled by bus yesterday. We had a pleasant surprise. At our transport point it is sometimes difficult to know where the bus stop is. A man told me I was at the bus stop and ask me which bus I was waiting for. It turns out he lives in my building. How delightful!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 17:23:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/08/15/i-needed-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/08/15/i-needed-to.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Second Anniversary</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today Nick and I celebrate our second anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick and I had a rocky start. I was originally matched with a different dog, Chance. Chance did everything I asked to do except go fast. I decided I didn’t want to bring a dog home that would likely slow down and then I would be very frustrated. I asked for a new dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chance left in the morning. I went to lunch dogless. At lunch I learned one of the other students had to leave class due to an injury. I even passed him as he was leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my room, my instructor brought my dog to me. I was in love immediately–a yellow Labrador Retriever male–big and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Full disclosure,” my instructor said. “This was Stanley’s dog.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always felt badly that in order to get Nick Stanley had to get hurt. If only he had received Chance and I was initially paired with Nick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what this was all about– Do things happen for a reason? Well, I’ve always been glad Nick was not paired with a newby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick has always been a difficult dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nick doesn’t like obedience. He remains a toddler. “Why?” Why do your want me to sit now? Why must I lay down? Once Nick figures this out for imself, he is quite willing to do so. He has finally figured that when people get up at the Sharing of the Peace at church, we are not preparing to leave the service.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nick continues to be difficult to park. We go out. Nick does number one. Then Nick often is willing to start to go inside. Then he will literally make a U-turn and return to the grass for number two.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nick came home with an ear infection. I treated that. Soon afterwards, Nick’s foot became infected. Licking. Licking. Licking. The vet decided he had a condition called Canine Atopic Dermatitis. I think of it as itching from the inside out. They tell me it is genetic. He is on a grain free diet which I must supplement with canned pumpkin and a laxative. My initial problems parking Nick may have been caused by Nick being so uncomfortable on grass. It is still amazing to me that Nick worked as well as he did with his medical issues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick still goes fast. He has never slowed down. He marks his territory, sniffs poles, gets distracted by other dogs. I often wonder if he was a C student. He learns slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this said, I never thought about returning him. He was my forever dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is working here in the city, on buses, vans and busy city streets. He can see a route once and follow many turns inside a busy building. He is learning to talk to me about needing to park, about an empty water bowl and a late dinner. He is exploring talking to me when it is time to get up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a happy day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 21:57:38 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/08/02/today-nick-and.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/08/03/today-nick-and.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Standing At the Bus Stop</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Took the bus this morning to Pilates. Standing at the bus stop. Standing at the bus stop. Standing at the bus stop where is the bus? One lane only at the airport is delaying my bus and all the other buses that have to go through there. Finally get on the bus after I am supposed to be there. As the class is one on one, I texted the instructor and all was well. We get to the transfer station. Usually, I stay on the bus. However,Today it is everyone off the bus. It is 35 minutes late they say. So we are told to walk to the bus behind us. A nice lady asks if she can help me and she and her husband see to it that I get on the bus which is a very good thing because there is a high step up onto the bus. Connect with my instructor and have a very good session. Afterwords, we stop at a taco stand and I get to vegan tacos, chips and guacamole. Delicious. Will stop at there again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 16:33:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/27/took-the-bus.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/27/took-the-bus.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>4th of July Parade</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nick and I marched in the Bay View 4th of July parade. I say “marched”. We walked. Nick thought it was quite strange to walk in the street. My walking companion was concerned that we stayed together and marched sort of in formation. Nick was fascinated by the people and dogs along the parade route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in a parade is very different than watching a parade go by. There is little sense of being part of a whole. There was me, Nick, my walking companion, Nancy, and perhaps a few other church members but no sense of the entire parade. There was no band playing patriotic music–at least not close enough for us to hear. Although there was a sense of community beforehand, people immediately split off to have ice cream individually and then break away to walk home. I won’t know for a couple days how Nick feels about streets as we have no plans until Friday night. It is so hot out. He was good with sidewalks and curbs on the way home and there were no vehicles near us during the parade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 20:36:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/04/nick-and-i.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/05/nick-and-i.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Country House Murders</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having just finished reading &lt;em&gt;Closed Casket&lt;/em&gt; by Sophy Hannah, I must conclude I love country house murder mysteries. Properly speaking, Lily Oaak is not a country house. It is the extended family home in the country. Nevertheless, a number of suspects are confined to the property until the murder is solved. Hannah is writing more Hercule Poirot mysteries in conjunction with Christie’s estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Poirot makes an excursion to England (We only have telephone conversations from there.) this mystery does not have a lot of toing and froing which often makes mysteries tedious. Of course witnesses are re-interviewed. Both Inspector Edward Catchpool and Poirot keep talking to both guests and residents of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a much better book than &lt;em&gt;The Monogram Murders&lt;/em&gt; and I am looking forward to the next novel in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 20:29:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/04/having-just-finished.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/05/having-just-finished.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Thunderstorm</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After several days of heat indexes is in the 90s and 100s, it was good to take Nick out during a mild thunderstorm and experience 75° weather and light rain Nice big fat raindrops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 17:31:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/01/after-several-days.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/07/01/after-several-days.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Furniture</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking around my apartment, it is clear I do not put a value on furniture. I have a table and chairs from IKEA and I sit on the couch from hospice. The other furniture is from family, hand me downs, some are called antiques now and some collectibles. Well, I guess I have collected them. Spending a lot on furniture apparently is not something I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 17:48:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/24/looking-around-my.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/24/looking-around-my.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Taking Charge</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Caitlin was a take charge dog. I pointed ahead and said, ”forward.” She hung a left and trudged up our intended sidewalk. I was certain she was saying to herself, “Blind people don’t know anything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the street and went up onto the sidewalk. “Forward,” I said to Elwood. He just stood there, looking around. He radiated panic. Straight ahead was grass. The sidewalk which led over the bridge went ahead of us one step to the left. What to do? Go forward and be scolded for stepping off the sidewalk while carrying out a command or turn left in order to go forward. I slowly recognized his dilemma and gave him the left and then forward commands to get home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today Nick struggled to do the right thing. We crossed the street and he turned right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forjard,” I said. Nick turned right. He started up a sidewalk leading to a house. I brought him back to the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;?Right,” I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick went up onto the grass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;?Phui,” I said. “Not on the grass.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out there was a tree with branches overhanging the sidewalk. I had scolded Nick for running me into foliage several days agago.Z we went further down the sidewalk, Nick was distracted by a barking dog. We ended up on the grass. Much scolding enensued.Standing on the grass, I instructed Nick to get going again. I stepped back as I tend to crowd Nick so he can’t turn properly. Nick continued to hold his ground. ×Forward,” had no effected. Neither did “Hup up.” I tried not to start moving myself. Nick after all is the guide dog. I point and repeated my cocommands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Nick moved down the slope to a curb. Was there no sidewalk on this side of the street? Possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed and found the sidewalk on the other side, went to the corner, crossed back and reworked the sidewalk which was in tact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned Nick around again and he again struggled to be on the sidewalk with the overhanging tree. Happily, Nick stayed on the sidewalk to the next cocorner.I am still coming to terms with Nick’s way of telling me what I am suggesting is a bad idea. I don’t know if he will become more assertive. In this case, he needed to turn in an entirely different direction to regain the sidewalk. With Nick’s great speed and strength, it is difficult for me to to understand how complient Nick really is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 19:45:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/09/caitlin-was-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/10/caitlin-was-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Smith College Ladies</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Early this morning I heard a promo for an NPR program interviewing the president of Smith College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young, my mother took us to the Smith College book sale in Princeton. We went more than a single time I am sure. The ladies–you could not call them anything else–were very proper and precise. My mother commented later that they were the upperclass of Princeton society. What else? They graduated from Smith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother must have bought books. I suspect they were novels. My encounter with the Smithies was when my mother paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, these women must have married well. They served their community by volunteering for worthy causes and raising money for their alma mater to educate more women for their new place in society. #WriteEveryDay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 08:54:28 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/08/smith-college-ladies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/08/smith-college-ladies.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Writing Plan of Sorts</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;for me. I thought I would try #WriteEveryDay. I wanted to start on June  1st, but obviously that did not come to pass. Nevertheless, I still want to write regularly. That doesn’t actually mean that I will post every day. The writing may not be in a form to post or it may be too private to post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not an avid reader of memoirs or autobiographies. However, I am frequently drawn to the idea of writing a memoir–not of a particular time in my life but different sketches of things I remember. More and more I am sharing little stories with my family. I often begin talking with my grandchildren: “When I was a girl…” It sounds so old-fashioned as if I were on the prairie. (Can you tell I’ve moved to the Midwest?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also noticed that I want to write about my experiences in my new city. I am taking buses, exploring new organizations and meeting new people. So much of my storytelling is shared with my friends. As I think this is vital, I am also aware that these stories are ephemeral. Yet I tell them over and over again with each new person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should these stories last? The right to be forgotten has raised this question. Should some things just go away? Are these stories important just for an hour, a day or a week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have discovered that my little stories are fun to look at later. In this vain, I want to start capturing them. The only way to do this is to write them down or record them. I can do both or either as I chchoose.Huzzah. Here is a page of writing for today. It may be more like The Artist’s Way daily pages, but at least it’s writing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 14:44:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/02/194423.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/06/02/194423.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>I didn’t blog every day</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Clearly I did not keep up with my plan to blog every day. I wasn’t prepared to do that. That is my learning for this month. I really need to prepare a list of topics to write about and not just expect them to present themselves without my intervention. I also need to plan for busy days when there isn’t time to write well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is your favorite emoji? Write something, a poem, a few lines, a whole story, based on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 20:10:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/28/i-didnt-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/29/i-didnt-blog.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Getting Organized</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I  did not write yesterday. Even though my plan was to write every day, the only thing I wrote was a list of things to write today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I did do was purchase &lt;a href=&quot;https://red-sweater.com&quot;&gt;MarsEdit&lt;/a&gt; so that I can fully access my [micro.blog(https://rill.micro.blog).  The iOS app is not fully accessible; neither is the web site. This makes editing my posts difficult if not impossible after they are posted. With &lt;a href=&quot;https://red-sweater.com&quot;&gt;MarsEdit&lt;/a&gt; I can work on my Mac and fix any mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I did not realize initially was that my blog posts were in plain text. My markdown was not working because I had not set up an “About” page.  I will have to make sure they are now properly formatted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still pretty shaky with MarsEdit. I hope I can become more proficient in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying to write this post using my Braille display. It is quite hard at the moment because I am using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a new app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my Mac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;andthe Braille display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am shaky using the Braille display connected to the Mac and I haven’t consulted the documentation. Soon I will have to look up how to control the Mac with this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later …  Markdown is working on the site. I used different ways of indicating unordered lists and different strategies for posting  so the lists look different even in the same post:* simple lists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;white bullets* and regular bullets
In any case, MarsEdit 
is working with my blog &lt;a href=&quot;rill.micro.blog&quot;&gt;rill.micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;.
#BlogEveryDay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 14:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/08/getting-organized.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/08/getting-organized.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Another Day At Home</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been another day at home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;no appointments&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;very cold weather&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;lots of odds and ends to do&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly did I do today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I created my shopping list in the Pick and Save app. Although it makes more sense to make a list instead of adding my items to the shopping cart, (I won’t checkout from the cart.), the app is set up to add to the cart and it is an extra step, as far as I can tell, to add something to the shopping list. The cool thing about the shopping list is that you can check off the item presumably when you put it into your cart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I am buying more because I am able to peruse the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I recorded a quick demo of the &lt;em&gt;Tunein Live&lt;/em&gt; Alexa skill for the Dot To Dot podcast. It is a paid skill with a 7-day free trial. It gives me access to Tunein premium content. I pay for this on my phone. (I pay a premium there.) It is a lot cheaper on my Amazon Echo. I started Tunein Premium originally because I had access to a variety of audio books as part of my subscription. I figured if I read a book a month I broke even. The books have been dropped from the program and I have been meaning to cancel my subscription. I can get my baseball games, but it is cheaper to use my dedicated MLB subscription. Besides, the baseball stream on my phone was not as reliable as the dedicated app. So why would I want to pay for &lt;em&gt;Tunein Live&lt;/em&gt;? I can stream some premium stations like Aljazeera English, C-Span and Young Turks.  It is far more likely that I will stream these at home rather than when I am out and about. I do drop into a baseball game when I have some down time when I am away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I did the laundry. Laundry is manageable when the machines are in your home. When they are coin-operated and downstairs, they are barely tolerable. There is coming and going, setting timers and discovering that half the machines are out-of-order.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I caught up with a young friend from guide dog school. It was good to hear her voice over audio messages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I posted to Facebook to see how other guide dog handlers find bus stop poles. They mostly assured me that my dog would catch on if I use the bus frequently which I currently do not do. If I get the route to &lt;a href=&quot;https://vision-forward.ord&quot;&gt;Vision Forward&lt;/a&gt; down, this may be the case. Whether Nick will start recognizing bus poles out in the wild remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 21:09:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/06/another-day-at.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/07/another-day-at.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title> Notetaker no more </title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my #BlogEveryDay goalssis to work on my Varioultra Braille Display and learn how to use it as a stand alone device. One of the display’s strengths is the ability to copy and paste text from the notetaker into a text field on my iPhone or iPad. Unfortunately, the Unified English Braille translation is poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Periods translate as “dd”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Random periods are written after the “with”, “and” and “for” contractions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “*” becomes “in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have switched to using the Braille display directly with my iPhone. We will see how this goes. I am still committed to using Unified English Braille rather than Grade 2 Braille. I figure that all new Braille will be in Unified English Braille and I want it solidly in my brain as I age. 
One of the fun things that came about using an app with markdown. I clicked on the preformatted link shortcut. I learned the left and right bracket signs in UEB as well as re-learning how to properly form a link. Everything looks different in Braille. That is what I get for spending my time writing markdown in Emacs on Linux.
 #BlogEveryDay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 19:09:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/05/notetaker-no-more.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/06/notetaker-no-more.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title> Mobility </title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I worked with my mobility instructor to understand how to take the bus to &lt;a href=&quot;http://vision-forward.org&quot;&gt;Vision Forward&lt;/a&gt;. I was relieved to learn that the bus stop near my apartment is easy to find. Both Nick and I were disappointed that I did not bring “you found the pole” treats with me. Blame the cold weather. The treats were in a lighter weight jacket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my instructor had another appointment after mine, I elected not to take the bus to the transfer point but to have him drive us there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get off the bus at the corner and then I have a choice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I can cross a busy street to get to the next bus stop. (There is a shelter there.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I can walk down a fairly long block to find another bus stop. It is right at the cornerand very easy to find.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the weather is good and there is time, walking a block sounds like a very easy solution to me. It also gives Nick a chance to relieve himself if necessary. Crossing busy streets is not always a comfortable option. It means listening very carefully to traffic changing direction when the light changes. With my moderate hearing loss in one ear (corrected by a hearing aid), I do not hear as well as I once did. Sometimes it is hard to pick up the surge of traffic and therefore have the full cycle to cross the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we simulated getting off the bus coming home from &lt;a href=&quot;http://visionccforward.org&quot;&gt;Vision Forward&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick was doing well, but he wanted to check the bus shelter and was not particularly interested in finding the pole. Again, I could not bribe him with treats. I suspect he will come through on the day I actually make the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to conquering this trip as I plan to be a frequent visitor to &lt;a href=&quot;http://vision-forward.org&quot;&gt;Vision Forward&lt;/a&gt;. I can take Paratransit at a higher cost. This means sharing rides and possibly spending much more time onboard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 17:55:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/04/mobility.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/04/mobility.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Election Day</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is Election Day in Wisconsin. My polling place is in my Community Room. No excuses. Go and vote in the Spring Election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I have been very timid going into a new situation. Somewhere along the line, I have become more bold. I walked in and said, to no one in particular, “Hello.” A woman directed me to someone who could help me register. I explained I was new to the city and needed to transfer my registration from another city in the state. Shockingly, I needed only to have lived for ten consecutive days at my current address. I am used to needing to live forty days in the county. I needed to show my ID and give my former address. I signed two papers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My new registration&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because my name was not in the book, the paper was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided not to have someone fill out my ballot for me. I used the talking voting machine for the first time. It took a little while to set it up. It is not used often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now know to bring my own wired headphones. I had to use the provided ones and the sanitation issues could be a concern. I had to adjust the volume and the speed of the speech. I wanted it loud and fairly slow so I could really understand what I was doing. This is an election after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Wisconsin, we use paper ballots. The ballot is fed into the machine and there is a pause. I assume the machine is scanning the ballot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After everything was set up, I listened to the instructions. The buttons are different shapes and large. Controls are labeled in Braille. I used a right arrow to move from contest to contest. I used the up and down arrows to review my selections. When I was done with each contest, I pressed the square button which is labeled with an s for select.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, I had a chance to review my choices and hit the final select button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a significant amount of clanking while the machine actually marked the ballot and then spit it out. After that, I just needed to insert it into the slot to be counted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the poll with a “I voted” sticker, making sure it was right side up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poll worker remarked that we could at least get the sticker right side up because so much else in the world was up side down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered that she made such a reference. I did not think election workers could make any such comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was five I went with my mother to vote. The voting machines were mechanical. You step into the booth, close the curtain and pull down the levers associated with each of the candidates you want. When you are finished, you slide the curtain back. There is a wonderful mechanical sound as the votes are tallied. At the end of the day, the poll officials will open the back and get the vote count for each machine. I once brought two kids, one guide dog and mzf into the booth. That was certainly chummy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to 1956.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A state trooper wasalw on duty at the polling place. (I don’t know if Wisconsin has a police presence. I will have to inquire.) I knew the trooper. I went to school with his daughter. I went up to him and opened my coat in order to show him all the election buttons I was wearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This caused a commotion. Displaying the buttons is considered electioneering at the polls which is illegal so I had to close my coat very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am certain one of the buttons was “I Like Ike”. I have no idea what the others were. #BlogEveryDay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 19:33:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/03/today-is-election.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/04/today-is-election.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Silent Phone</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I think I have spent an hour this morning trying to work out why my iPhone was not speaking. Here is what I tried:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I rebooted the iPhone several times.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I connected my Braille display and VoiceOver was working. If it was not on, the Braille display would not work. I turned VoiceOver on and off via Siri several times. When I turned VoiceOver off with the Braille display connected, my display on the Braille notetaker went blank.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I went into the Sound Settings and found the volume was at an acceptable level. I raised and lowered it. I was able to do this because VoiceOver spoke on this screen. When I left the sound settings screen, VoiceOver stopped speaking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I went through all the VoiceOver settings. I could find nothing wrong. After all, the iPhone worked just fine when I plugged it in to charge before I went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I played with the mute switch. (I never remember which way is mute and which way is unmuted.) Unfortunately, the Internet does not tell you which way to click the mute switch to be unmuted. The only description I found referred to a red or orange strip which becomes visible when unmuted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I searched the web. Nothing I found was particularly useful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I tried to play an audio file. I heard nothing. This alarmed me. All sound was turned off somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My phone turned off. I woke it up and reviewed the lock screen. I noticed information about my bluetooth headphones. Didn’t I read something about this before? Why were my headphones coming up here anyway? They are in my pocketbook. I have not taken them out for days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to find my bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could hear the. audio file still playing. The problem resolved itself immediately: Sound was being directed through my headphones rather than through my speaker. I turned off the headphones and voila, sound came back to my iPhone. Why hadn’t I thought of this before? It has happened before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not think of it because I hadn’t used the headphones for almost a week and my phone had worked fine yesterday. What changed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the crate belonged to my previous guide dog, I would blame Elwood. He was a sneak and. a cheat and I loved him dearly. Turning on my headphones by bumping my bag would have seemed just good fun to him. But Nick does not have that sort of humor. There is nothing sneaky about Nick at all. #BlogEveryDay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 20:35:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/02/013517.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/03/013517.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Walking Cold</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is Easter. This is a happy day. Unfortunately, it is colddd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I bundled up to walk up Holy Hill with my family. The temperature was in the forties. It rained earlier in the morning, but cleared a little later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to go to a Vietnamese restaurant. Sadly, it was closed and the building is for rent. Although the food there was good, the facility was run down and not inviting to the public. It was probably under capitalized as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we started looking for another place to eat since we all were quite hungry. The first restaurant we tried was very busy. They invited us to eat on the unheated enclosed patio. This was not an option for us. There were high tops and the room was gloomy. It might be acceptable later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Restaurants were pretty slim on the ground, but we found a custard place. Not being a Wisconsin native, I imagined a custard place to be just about ice cream. I did not realize these are regular restaurants that are known for burgers. Happily for me, they also serve deep fried cod and good French fries. The triple scoop Hot Fudge Heaven Sundae is excellent. It comes without whipped cream. I learned in college when I lived in western Pennsylvania that whipped cream is not a part of a traditional Sundae. And the decaf coffee is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking the Stations of the Cross is supposed to be a reverent, meditative and solemn experience. I went with an eight-year-old and a four-year-old. It was loud, energetic and involved running and shrieking. Reading the name of each station meant screaming the words rather than speaking loudly. Nick, my Seeing Eye dog, thought that copying the kids’ actions was the way to go so my “walk” up Holy Hill had a lot of jerks and swerves in it. Some of the hills are steep. The blacktop is in good shape, but the drop offs are fairly steep. I was nervous I would trip or step off the side and fall down the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the stairs. The stairs are well-maintained like the rest of the path. There are handrails. The stairs, too, are steep. The first set of stairs is about a story high — thirteen steps. The second set of stairs is thirty-three steps, one for each year of Jesus’ earthly life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found the stations we missed on our earlier visit in the fall. They commemorate Jesus’ burial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I thought yesterday was chilly, today is down right wintry. I put on my knitted headband, my light weight gloves and my winter coat. I also wore a sweater because the downstairs hall at the church is very cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put on my new jeans, but Amazon sent me regular length ones instead of petite. I reordered using Alexa. This is disappointing. I won’t go through the hassle of returning them. Perhaps my daughter-in-law will be able to hem them or at the very least cut them off. They are a little roomy too, but they are still unwashed. I need to use a lot of heat to dry my clothes since apartment coin operated dryers are not known for their nuanced drying capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned to attend the pot luck dinnerafter church at a nearby home. I packed the challah bread I bought yesterday and a frozen pound of butter in a backpack. Off we went&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were approaching East Dewy Place, Nick stopped. I checked for the curb. Instead of finding the down curb, I found the sidewalk missing. Very carefully, I tried to determine the depth of the missing sidewalk section, mindful that this could be a deep hole. Nick has no way to indicate this. I have been known to be over confident in the past and I almost get myself into real trouble by freelancing without Nick’s guidance. I quickly hit dirt, but decided against seeing if it was only one missing section I needed to negociate. There was construction debris around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in the week, on our way home from the dentist, some trucks were working across the street further south. I thought this construction might be related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We backtracked and went around the block. I crossed East Dewy Place, hoping we would be able to get back on the sidewalk. No luck. We wound up on dirt and later on the street. It took me a little time to figure this out and work Nick carefully along the side of the street. Nick seemed uncertain how to proceed. Perhaps I was too bossy and did not give him room to work. This is often one of my failings as a guide dog user. We worked sideways until we arrived back at the sidewalk. I did not execute this as well as I would like. My explanation is that I did not assess the situation properly. The good news is that only local traffic is allowed on the street and few cars traveled past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meant a much bigger rerouting. We walked over to South Chase Street. Nick offered to take me to the dentist. We walked along East Oklahoma and crossed it when the Milwaukee County Transit bus crossed. With a detour down South Adams Avenue to investigate another dog, we arrived at church nearly halfway through the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of the morning was Dick’s adult baptism. I did not miss that. There was a reception afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting with friends, coffee and a light lunch, I described my adventure. A ride home appeared. I gratefully took it. I sent the bread to the pot luck with my regrets. I was exhausted after the longer than usual walk and the stress of two detours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 20:23:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/01/april-entry-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/04/02/april-entry-today.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Camp Nanowrimo</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;April is about to start. I have decided to participate in Camp Nanowrimo this year with no clear goal in mind. Two possible writing goals are on the  table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continue to work on my Three Laws of Magic novel. With a modest goal — the minimum goal of 10,000 words — this seems doable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use the 30 days of April for a sustainable Write Every Day goal and see if I can write something I can blog every day. At some level, this is a harder goal because it requires me to plan and to execute. I cannot let the day’s activities dictate wether I write or not. April is shaping up to be a busy month for me. However, to make the minimum goal of 10,000 words, I need only write 334 words a day to achieve it. I don’t have to write this many words every day. Some days I will write less and some days I will write more. The point is, to achieve my own Write Every Day goal, I must write daily.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either case, I want to write on my Braille notetaker and prepare the day’s writing this way to expand and cement my knowledge of my Braille notetaker and become more familiar with its editing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 15:34:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://Rill.micro.blog/2018/03/30/camp-nanowrimo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Rill.micro.blog/2018/03/30/camp-nanowrimo.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
